Good for you,
you made it this far!
Congratulations! And thanks for sticking through the whole course with me.
If you feel like it was a useful experience and you learned a few things, please leave a review that
will help me improve things with the course going forward and it will let me know what I'm doing right
and what I'm doing wrong.
Your review could help other prospective students understand if they should give this course a try.
I really appreciate that feedback and it would be great if you could take a minute after this and leave
a review.
Okay, so where do you go from here?
What's next?
Well, there is obviously a lot more to learn.
We covered a lot of the basics of Spark but, you know, there's more to the field of data science than
big data as a whole.
If you want to sort of desktop reference to refer to instead of videos there are some books that I can
recommend about spark.
I won't make any money from these or anything so don't worry about that,
I'm not trying to sell you anything but these books I have personally enjoyed and I recommend giving
them a look at. The O'Reilly series I think is very useful.
They have a book called Learning spark that I found to be a helpful reference while learning. It has
a lot of good little snippets and code examples in there that you might find useful
and if you're going to be using spark for some real machine learning and data mining work, I also really
like advanced analytics with Spark,
also from the O'Reilly press, it takes more of a data mining view of things.
So, you know, it goes more to death with things like M.L. lib.
What I really like about this book is that it doesn't assume that you're a machine learning or data
mining expert,
it takes the time to actually review things like what is K Means clustering and things like what is
Pearson correlation metric all about?
It doesn't automatically assume that you're already an expert in this stuff and it's written in a very
conversational tone and I like it for that reason - because you know data mining doesn't have to be hard,
machine learning doesn't have to be hard.
The concepts themselves are actually pretty straightforward once you grasp them,
you just have to get through the terminology and all the fancy language.
On the other hand, there's a book called Data algorithms by O'Reilly, a very thick book,
though it's not really spark specific. It's actually written for Hadoop and map reduce with Spark
is kind of a third option. In the book
they have a bunch of recipes for different types of problems you might encounter in the machine learning
world and some sample solutions to those problems, using both map reduce and spark side by side.
It does spend a lot of time on the map reduce side of things so I'm not really sure this one is written
with Spark in mind specifically the tone is also a little bit more academic, so you might find it a little
bit less accessible if you're new to the field, but there are some very useful recipes in there.
So my recommendation would be to go check out the table of contents on your favorite booksellers website
and just keep that list handy.
I mean, beyond the world of spark itself, there's obviously a lot more to the world of data mining and
data science in general. Just knowing spark does not make you a data scientists that will make lots and
lots of money, learning about data mining in general is a good idea as well.
As I mentioned, the advanced analytics with Spark book touches on that a little bit but picking up a
course like statistics for dummies is probably a good place to start if you're totally new to that field.
Be sure to also look for courses on machine learning and data mining,
those are probably the keywords you want to look for in data science in a more general term.
There's a lot more to learn there as well.
Alright, well I hope that gives you a good starting point for your next step toward a career as a data
scientist or if you're already a data scientist or an engineer working at a large software company that
has lots of big data to process,
I hope you now have a new tool under your belt.
Spark is a very fast, easy and efficient way to manage large amounts of data on a cluster.
If you have access to one, or even if you don't, EMR is a good way to get one for pretty cheap.
Hey, it's been a good ride.
Thanks for coming along with me.
I appreciate it.
There is one more bonus lecture at the end of this course
so feel free to give that a watch, that also gives me a chance to tell you about some other stuff that
I can offer you. Again,
thank you
and if you haven't already, please don't forget to take a minute and leave your review on the course.
Thanks a lot.