So let's go ahead
and review the code here and then we'll kick it off.
Not a lot of code here right,
so even though it's applying
a very sophisticated model
called Alternating Least Squares
to do movie recommendations here,
using that algorithm is quite simple.
All the complexity is hidden from us,
thanks to Spark ML.
So we import the stuff we need,
most notably spark.ml.recommendation
and from there we're gonna import the ALS module.
And let's skip ahead to where the code actually starts
in the main body of the script.
We create our SparkSession object here as always
we'll call it ALSExample.
And now we need to construct a schema
for use in loading the u.data file
from the ml-100K datasets
because sadly that file does not have a hetero.
But that's fine,
we'll just do it the hard way.
So we create a StruckType in four StruckFields
that correspond to the userID
and movieID rating and timestamp columns in that data file.
And we specify the data types for them
and they are nullable.
Next we load up the movieNames file,
and this is actually not doing anything with Spark
this is just using the sys and codec libraries
to open up that file locally on my local file system,
from where I'm running the driver script.
And we're just gonna keep that in memory
as a dictionary in our Python Script.
And that's okay because it's a small file.
In the real world you might still do this
because this is a case
where there's fewer items than people, right?
So there's not all that many movies in the world.
Even if you look at every movie ever made,
it will probably still fit in memory on a single machine.
So don't distribute something if you don't have to,
if all you need to do is have that lookup at the end,
when we're storing the final data,
the results that we're getting back from the cluster,
why our waste resources on the cluster
distributing that around if you don't have to.
So that's what we're doing here.
We're just loading up the u.ITEM file here
in the specified encoding for the character
encoding used by that file.
We'll ignore errors, that's fine.
And we just go through every line in the file,
split it based on the pipe character
and build up that movieNames dictionary,
assigning movie IDs to their movie name,
read in from that u.ITEM file.
And we return that resulting dictionary as movieNames.
And here we return it as the, the variable names rather.
Next, we load up the ratings data,
and this is our so called Big data.
So we are going to load that into a dataframe,
so it can be distributed
for that we just use spark.read
we specify that we have a tab-delimited CSV file.
So it's not really a CSV file.
It's a TSV file,
but it works the same way.
You can still treat it as a CSV file.
The unique delimiter, that's fine.
We passed in our schema that we had defined before,
and that we have a handy-dandy data frame
containing all of our movie ratings
with that particular schema.
So we're gonna have a userID, movieID, rating
and timestamp column in that resulting data frame.
Now we get into the meat of recommendations
and using Spark ML.
So just like we saw in the slides,
we create a new ALS object,
that's Alternating Least Squares,
which is just a specific recommendation algorithm
that we're using here.
And it's the only one that Spark ML provides.
So we don't have much to choose from there I'm afraid
(chuckles)
we set the hyperparameters in this case,
we're setting it to 5 and 0.01.
I don't remember where I got those from exactly,
it might just be straight from the example code,
but I think I might've tried a few different ones
when I was first writing this to see what worked the best.
We tell it with the names of the userID,
itemID and rating columns are
that we assigned up here in our structure
for the movie schema and load it in.
So now we have an ALS model that knows
how to deal with that training data.
So we just call fit
and pass in that training dataframe.
Now in the real world,
you might wanna actually split
that into a training set and a testing set
like we've seen in some other examples,
but to keep things simple,
we're just gonna use the entire dataset
and train the model using it.
If you wanted to actually review the results
and measure whether these are good recommendations or not,
you could do something like reserving some of that data
for testing purposes and seeing if you're able
to successfully predict the ratings
that people really gave to the movies that they rated.
But, well I don't wanna get into
the nuances of evaluating recommender systems.
I literally have a whole course on that.
That's a big topic.
All right. So now that we have that,
we just need to get a prediction from it.
And it turns out that's one of the hardest part
of using this, this code here.
So the way it works is you construct
a dataframe of user IDs that you want
to generate recommendations for.
So, unfortunately there's not a simple API here
where you can say,
just give me recommendations for this user ID.
There used to be back in spark.mllib.
So and some things have gotten worse in my opinion,
but hey, that's the price of going
with dataframes for everything.
So the first thing we need to do is figure out
which user ID do we want to get recommendations for.
And we're actually gonna pass that in
as a command-line argument to this script
and to extract that argument,
we call (sys.argv [1])
that just gets the first parameter
that was passed in on the command line
when we invoke this script,
0 would be the name of the script itself.
We convert that to an integer
because we said that user IDs are integers above here.
So which user ID should we look at?
Well, if you wanna get a sort of,
intuitive sense of whether or not
we're producing good recommendations or not,
we need a user that we understand,
someone that reflects maybe our own interests.
And then we can say, well,
are these reasonable recommendations for me?
And that's what I've done.
So if we go to the course materials,
lemme pull that up real quick here.
And we go into the ml-100k folder here,
and let's take at look u.data.
You can see I've actually modified
the file to include a User 0 that wasn't there before.
So what I've done is I've made some fake ratings here
for user ID zero,
and that's gonna be my test case.
And as I recall, this means that I loved Star Wars
and the Empire Strikes Back
but I hated the movie Gone with the Wind.
That's what these movie IDs correspond to.
You can look those up in the u.dot item folder in here.
So this is basically someone
who likes science fiction movies,
but you know, isn't so much into classic romance movies.
Right?
So that kinda describes me.
So I can take a look at the recommendations
that I get for this fictitious User 0
and see if they make sense or not.
If that doesn't sound like you feel free
to generate your own User ID 0
by editing the u.data file.
with whatever text editor you like
and create your own little fake persona here,
you know, put in some movies that you've loved
some movies you've hated and see what comes out of it.
So having generated that fake User ID 0
and added that into our dataset,
we're gonna pass in 0 as our parameter there,
and that will be our user ID.
So we need to construct a schema for that as well,
because everything has to be a dataframe now.
So we can start to schema.
The user ID is an integer type,
and that is the one field in the structure
of that dataframe.
So we only have one column
in this dataframe
that we're fabricating for creating recommendations,
and that is a user ID column.
We then need to create a dataframe from that user ID.
And to do that, we need to use this weird syntax here.
Again, this is kind of a quirky thing with a Pyspark.
It needs to be a list of columns here.
So we can't just pass in a single column here.
We have to have actually say "userID,"
and then nothing, just to sort of trick Spark
into thinking that this is actually a dataframe
that we're constructing here.
So we have basically a,
a list of rows and within each row
we have a list of columns.
So that's why we have
this double square bracket thing going on here.
And we furthermore pass in that userSchema
to apply that schema to that data as
we're converting it to a dataframe.
So what we should end up with here is a user's dataframe
that consists of a userID column
with a single row consisting of the value 0.
And that is what we need to pass
into model.RecommendForUserSubset.
What we're saying here is I want you to generate
recommendations for all the users in the user's dataframe.
In our example,
there's only one user, User ID 0
and generate 10 recommendations,
the 10 best recommendations for each user.
We will then collect that back to the driver script.
So that will take all that work back from the cluster
and return the final results
to our recommendations structure here.
So then we just have to print them out.
We say, here are the top 10 recommendations
for the user ID,
whatever the user ID is that we passed in
which we intend to be 0 and printing that out
actually it turns out to be a little bit complicated too.
We iterate through each recommendation that comes back,
we extract the row.
So at this point,
userRecs is gonna be in this format.
It's gonna be a tuple of user ID
and the row object associated with that user ID,
actually a list of row objects associated with that user ID.
And that will consist of a movieID and a rating,
a movieID and a rating, so on and so forth.
So for every user ID,
we get back a list of a rows
for every unique rating prediction for that user ID.
So then we have to go through
each one of those individual recommendations
in our case, we're just gonna get back
a single userID row for a User ID 0.
So we need to iterate through
each movieID rating tuple row,
and extract that movieID
and extract that rating from that row.
All right.
So then we need to make this human readable.
So we use that names dictionary that we loaded up earlier
to convert that movieID into a movie name
and print out the result.
We just print movieName
and the predicted rating for that movie.
All right.
So with that, let's kick it off.
And again, we need to do this with a parameter.
So let's first go into where my course materials are,
(keyboard clacking)
And we'll kick this off with a spark-submit.
And the name of the script
is movie-recommendations-als-dataframe.py.
And we will pass in 0 as a parameter and kick it off.
And when we come back in our next video,
we'll take a look at the results.
Keep you hanging.