All right, so it finished and it didn't take too long.
And we have some results here,
for my fictitious user ID zero who remember,
loves star Wars and hates gone with the wind.
And these are the recommendations it came up with.
Now I don't know if you're familiar with these movies,
I'm certainly not though.
And to me these strike me is just terrible,
terrible, terrible recommendations.
What do these have to do with science fiction?
Nothing as far as I can tell,
these could have just been,
chosen at random.
What went wrong here?
Like it is extremely confident,
that I'm going to love the movie Mina Tannenbaum.
Now, to be fair I've never heard of that movie,
maybe it's awesome,
let's look it up.
So I used to work for MDB.
Let's check our MDB.
This film tells a story of two girls
who have totally different character.
They know each other since their childhood,
this has nothing to do with anything,
that is even remotely related to star wars.
What the heck.
So what went wrong here?
Well we can see that this algorithm was easy to use,
but for our dataset,
for the ML 100 K dataset,
it's not producing very good results at all.
Let's talk a little bit about why that might be.
So what happened here?
Well, first of all we didn't put a whole lot of effort
into finding those right hyperparameters.
And like I said,
we could use a train test framework
to evaluate the performance of various
permutations of those hyperparameters,
those maxlterations and,
regularization parameters and whatnot.
And it is possible to measure the accuracy
of those rating predictions.
If you happen to predict a movie,
that somebody in your test,
data set already watched and rated,
then you can get a measure of whether or not
you're actually reading that person's mind
effectively or not.
But this gets really difficult with recommender systems
because it's what we call a sparse data problem.
The vast majority of movies have not been seen
by most people so,
you can't really evaluate whether your prediction
for a movie rating is a good one or not in most cases.
So it's kind of hard to say, what is a good recommendation.
Sometimes you have to start with more of a
qualitative assessment which is what we just did there.
But I have tried different hyperparameters,
I've tried normalizing the ratings,
I've tried everything I could think of,
to try to get better results out of that algorithm
and nothing really works.
Honestly I'm not convinced it's working properly internally.
I think there might be a bug in it somewhere
because it's that bad.
And the lesson here is,
putting your faith in a black box
is sometimes a dodgy thing to do.
So make sure that if you're gonna be using a
black box algorithm like spark ALS implementation,
you're evaluating the results before you bet the firm on it
before you actually put that in production
and stake your reputation on its results
or your business for that matter.
Ironically we got much better results
just using our homegrown collaborative filtering
example earlier in the course,
that produced much better recommendations.
Where we just took a more straightforward approach of
finding similar movies to movies each user liked.
So another lesson here is that,
complicated isn't always better.
Alternating these squares is a pretty fancy algorithm,
that really depends on having more data than we gave it.
I think that's the fundamental issue here.
But complicated isn't always better.
You know our simpler approach earlier in the course
was able to produce good results
even with this smaller dataset.
So never blindly trust your results
when you're analyzing big data,
small problems and algorithms can become bigger ones,
but often it's the quality of your input data,
that's the real issue.
I think you'll find that if you were to give
the ALS algorithm more data,
it would perform better.
I think this data sets its just,
too small for it to work with.
It's trying to find gradients in there that
there's just not enough data,
to find those gradients to begin with.
So that explains,
maybe a little bit of why we got
disappointing results from ALS there.
Again on larger situations using real data,
you might get better results,
but for the ML 100 K data set
this is not the best algorithm.
And again, the problem with ML in spark
is that you don't have a lot of algorithms to choose from.
That's not because they're lazy,
it's because there's only so many algorithms
that can be parallelized really.
Spark.ML though is really useful,
so don't let this get you down.
Let's go ahead and proceed to an example,
using something that machine learning is
more successful with,
linear regression we shouldn't be able to mess that up.
So let's move forward and redeem the value of Spark.ML.