So making movie recommendations
is a pretty tough thing to do with machine learning.
So let's step back a little bit and go to a simpler example
and that's linear regression.
And we're gonna do that using spark.ml
so we can scale this up to a massive data set
if we wanted to.
What is linear regression?
It's really simple.
All you're doing is fitting a line
to a data set of observations
and using that line to predict new values
that you haven't seen before.
So for example, in this graph,
we are trying to predict people's height
based on their weight.
Generally speaking,
the thing you're trying to predict is on the y-axis.
So we have this set of data sets
where we weight a bunch of people,
and we measure their height,
and then we made a plot of it on this scatterplot.
And given this scatterplot,
we can fit a line to it.
And the idea here is to just
try to find the line that minimizes the error
between the distance between each one of those points
and the distance to that line
and that's how linear regression works.
Once you have that line,
you can use that to make new predictions.
So you could take in someone who had a weight
that we've never seen before
and use that lined to predict their height.
It's really simple.
I mean, if you just remember high school level math,
you can have an equation of a line
in the form of a y-intercept and slope formula here
and here, we're just saying we have a slope of 0.6
and a y-intercept of 130.2
so we just plug in the weight to that
and you can predict a height.
It's high school algebra stuff.
I don't know why they call it regression.
It's kind of a confusing name.
Regression kind of implies that we're talking about
looking at the past.
In practice, for example,
this example has nothing to do with time at all.
So there are historical reasons why it's called regression,
but don't let the name confuse you.
Linear regression is just fitting a line to points
and using that line to make predictions
based on the previous points that you train that line to.
How does it work?
Well, uses a technique called least squares
and even though that does sound familiar
from what we just did with movie recommendations,
it's a simpler algorithm.
It's just minimizing the squared error
between each point in the line like we talked about.
Y squared-error,
that's just so that positive and negative
differences count the same really.
And yeah, we can just take that resulting line,
plug it into the slope intercept equation of the line
y equals mx plus b
and a little mathematical diversion here.
It's kind of interesting that the slope
ends up being the correlation between the two variables,
times the standard deviation in y
divided by the standard deviation in x.
And I just find that cool because
you kind of think of standard deviation sometimes
as sort of this arbitrary statistical measure,
but in fact, it has a real mathematical real world meaning
and this really makes that evident.
The y-intercept works out to be the mean of y
minus the slope times the mean of x.
So that's one way to compute the actual slope and intercept
of this line that you're fitting.
However, in the real world,
things aren't that neat,
you'll often have multiple dimensions,
meaning that you'll have more than one feature
that you're using to predict that label.
So maybe you'd be predicting someone's height
based not only on their weight,
but their ethnicity or where they live
or other things that might have
a correlation to their height.
When you're dealing with multi-dimensional spaces like that,
you need fancier techniques.
So the way that spark actually does linear regression,
it says spark streaming on the slide here
and there is a streaming version of this too.
But it uses a technique called stochastic gradient descent,
SGD for short.
And this is a ubiquitous algorithm
in the field of machine learning
and also in deep learning and neural networks.
This is not a course about that,
so I'm not gonna get too much into depth about it,
just know that it uses SGD under the hood
to implement linear regression.
Using it is simple,
just like it was for ALS,
the differences were gonna get better results this time.
So you just set up your model like this,
you can just say linear regression
and pass into your hyper parameters,
max iteration, regularization parameter,
elastic net parameter.
Again, a big part of the job is just gonna be
finding the best hyper parameters
to use for the best results
and you can start from what you see in the examples online
and that's usually a reasonable starting point.
You'll train the model
using your training data in a data frame
and make predictions using tuples that consist of a label
and a vector of features.
So in this case,
the label is the value we're trying to predict,
that's usually on your y-axis
and your feature will be on your x-axis
or other axes if you want to visualize it.
So you just train it with a bunch of known points,
and you predict new label values for given features
using the line that the model created.
And again, this can work with more than two dimensions,
that's the power of spark.ml's linear regression technique.
There are some things to be aware of when using it though.
First of all, stochastic gradient descent
doesn't really handle feature scaling very well.
So if you do have multiple features
that are in different scales,
that could be an issue.
It's going to assume that your data
is similar to a normal distribution.
So generally speaking,
you're gonna want to scale your data down
to fit something that's closer
to a normal distribution centered around zero,
and then scale it back up again when you're done
to get the best results.
If you have different features that have different scales,
like for example, if you're using people's weights,
that might be a very different scale from how old they are.
So those different scales can mess things up.
You need to have this sort of uniform scale in place
when you're training the model
and that's a little bit of extra work.
Also, it assumes that your y-intercept is zero
on the resulting line,
unless you call fit intercept true on it.
So some things to be aware of.
Let's go try it out.
So as an experiment,
we're going to fabricate some data for average page speed
and revenue generated from session data on an online store.
Now, the premise here is that we're trying to see
if there's a relationship between
how much money people spend
and how fast their page load experience was
while they were interacting with the website.
And this is something we really did
at Amazon a long time ago.
This was before
page speed was really a hot topic with Google and people.
And the reason that it's such a hot topic even now
is because yes, there is a correlation
between how much people engage with your website
and how much money they spend on your website
and how responsive your website is.
So can we predict revenue based on page speed
using a linear regression model?
Well, let's dive into the code and find out.
So the code here is pretty simple.
Most of the work is just in preparing our data
for use with the model, actually.
So we start off by creating our spark session.
And by the way, this config line here
for a spark.sql.warehouse.dir,
that's a window specific thing.
And it works around a bug
that I believe they fixed in spark three,
so you could actually get away
with removing that particular clause there,
if you want to just to simplify things.
We'll call it LinearRegression and getOrCreate session.
And we'll load up our regression.txt file
that we're gonna use to train our model.
So let's familiarize ourselves with that input data.
That's always an important step in machine learning.
Where is it regression.
There it is.
So you can see that we've already scaled this data down.
So even though this is supposed to represent
amount spent and page speed,
we've normalized that down to a normal distributions scale,
so we've already done the work of scaling everything down
to the ranges that the linear regression algorithm
works the best with.
So we have two columns of data here separated by a comma.
Let's see, what are we assuming that
these correspond to.
So let's take a look at the code here.
We load up at the regression.txt file
and then we map that splitting up based on the comma.
Note that we're actually using the RDD interface here
to parse that data out.
In this case, it's a little bit more straightforward.
So then we map x.
X represents each row of that RDD.
We extract the first column of information
and then a dense vector of the remaining columns.
So this is the format
that the linear regression algorithm is expecting.
It wants the first column to contain the label,
the thing we're predicting,
so in that case, it's gonna be amount spent.
That's what that first column represents in this case.
And then after that,
we have a list of all the features that we're using.
In our case, we only have one feature
which is the page speed
So going back to our data here,
that first column is going to be
a scaled down representation of amount spent,
the thing we're trying to predict, the label,
followed by all the features that we're using
to make that prediction for the label.
In this case, we only have one feature,
which is a representation of the page speed,
but you could have more than one.
So you could create a dense vector
of multiple features there
and do a multiple dimension regression just as easily.
Alright, moving on.
So now that we have that RDD,
we have to convert it to a DataFrame
and we're gonna cheat there
by just passing in this column names list here,
and passing that into the toDF function
to convert that RDD to a data frame with those column names.
So pretty straightforward.
So we're gonna end up with a label column
that contains that floating point value
that represents the amount spent,
and then we're going to have a features column
that contains a dense vector of feature information.
In this case, only a single value
will be inside that dense vector
and that is our representation of page speed.
All right, so that's the hard part.
Now let's actually split this up
into training data and testing data.
So spark provides a handy way of doing that
with the random split function on data frames
and this will do a 50/50 split of that data
and we'll use half of that data for training the model
and half of that data for evaluating the model.
The idea here is that you don't want to train the model
on the same data that you're gonna test it with.
It's kind of like cheating on a test.
So that's what we're doing here.
We extract train test zero and train test one
and assign that to trainingDF and testDF respectively.
Alright, now we're gonna create our linear regression model.
Again, a lot of the work is gonna be
in optimizing these hyper parameters.
These are reasonable starting values however,
but for best results,
you're gonna want to try different values
and see which ones work the best.
We then train it using the training data frame.
So that's the half of the data
that we randomly assigned for training purposes.
We just call fit on it
and now we have a model that we can use to make predictions.
So let's do that.
We'll call model.transform passing in our test data.
And we'll cash that set of results
so that we can do stuff with it.
So we need to print this out and see what we got.
So we'll start by extracting those predictions
and the known correct labels.
And to get things back into a format
that we can more easily process,
we're going to convert those back to RDDs.
So we'll start by selecting the prediction column,
that's going to be the predicted amount spent
and we we'll map that back
to just have a single value in it.
And similarly, we'll extract that single value
out of the label column as well.
All we're doing here is just simplifying this down
to an easier structure to use within Python here.
So we're taking what is sort of a complicated row object,
extracting the one thing in that row that we care about
and passing that back into our predictions
and labels object here.
We then call zip to zip them together.
So this is just gonna collect together
both the predicted and actual values for each point.
This is a little bit challenging
to wrap your head get around,
but it's not important guys.
This is not spark code.
All we're doing is printing out the stuff
in a way that makes sense for us to look at.
So we're gonna iterate through each prediction
in that prediction enabled zip together structure,
print them out and then stop our session and we're done.
So let's go ahead and kick this off.
Our new script name here is spark linear-regression.PY.
Let's kick it off
and make some predictions.
Now, the reason I kind of glossed over that whole zip thing
and how we're tying together the final results
is cause in the real world,
you wouldn't really be doing it that way.
You would actually be probably making some measure
of the accuracy of those predictions instead,
but I just want to simplify the results here
so you can see them in a format that's easier to understand.
So what we're seeing here is just the predicted value
and the actual value for everything in our test data.
So for every test point here,
this is the value that we predicted
the amount spent would be
and the actual value that was in our test data.
And just by eyeballing it,
you can see, well, it's okay.
It could be better.
They're in the same ballpark at least.
So that's cool.
So it kind of worked.
But the accuracy probably could be improved,
either by throwing more data at it
or maybe by playing with those hyper parameters.
And this is to be fair, a fake data set.
In the real world, you probably get much better results
by using real world data,
instead of data that are generated more or less at random.
So there you have it,
spark linear regression in action.
As you can see, it's still really easy to use.
The hard part is just in preparing your data
for training it with and once you have that,
it's very easy to generate a set of predictions
using new data that you haven't seen before.
So that is linear regression in spark.ml.
As you can see, that works a little bit better
and we get more reasonable results from that.
Also, keep in mind too,
that I skipped the step of scaling this backup.
So remember that we scaled all of our training data down
to be centered around zero
and be more or less plus or minus oneish in range.
We have to scale that back up to their proper range
to get final results from here as well.
These are all nuances of dealing with machine learning.
Not really spark issues,
but the important thing from a spark standpoint is
building a linear regression model in spark
is straightforward and using it is straightforward.
That's what you got to know.