All right.
So let's have a look at my solution for handling
that real estate data there, and trying to predict
the value of a house per unit area,
just based on the age of the house,
the distance of public transportation,
and the number of convenience stores.
So let's walk through my code here, and compare it to yours.
So we start off with our usual stuff of importing stuff.
There is an extra line here
that I haven't really used before.
That's just making sure that I have some backward
compatibility with a print function between Python three,
and Python two, but you don't don't necessarily need that.
Another thing you don't necessarily need is this line here.
If name equals main,
that's just there to protect this script
from if you were to run it from outside of a different
context than just running it as a standalone script.
So just a little bit of safety there that you,
just a good practice to include, but you don't need to.
Beyond that it's mostly what you've seen before.
So we start off by creating a Spark session
with a given app name, and we get our created.
We then load up our Dataframe.
So again, we have a header row here,
so we're just gonna use it, and load our data directly
into a Dataframe as opposed to an RDD here.
We'll just say spark.read.option header true.option
inferschema true, and it will just figure out
what that schema is, and convert that into a Dataframe,
after reading that data in from
the SparkCourse/realestate.CSV file.
And as always be sure to change that path,
if it's different for you.
Next we need to massage our data
into the format that our model expects.
And like I mentioned in the slides,
the easiest way to do this is actually by using
a VectorAssembler which we have imported up here with
pyspark.ml.feature import VectorAssembler.
We just construct a new VectorAssembler object,
and we set the names of the input columns
to this list of column names.
So our features will be the house age, the distance to MRT,
and the number convenience stores columns.
And then furthermore, we set the output column,
our label, if you will, to features.
And then we just use that assembler,
and pass in our data with the transform function.
So that we'll actually construct that vector of feature data
along with our output column as well.
And we will select price of unit area,
which is going to be our label column and features,
which will contain that vector of feature data.
All right, so now that we have that,
we can split our data into training
and testing data, if you want to, if you skip that,
that's okay I'll, I'll overlook that,
but we've seen that before.
So now we construct our decision tree regressor model,
and we tell it what the name of our features column is
it's called features,
and what the name of our label column is,
which is price of unit area.
Again, label is the thing we're trying to predict,
and features are the attributes that we are using
to try to make that prediction from.
Once we have that model defined,
we can fit it using our training data
by passing in the training Dataframe that we constructed
from that random split of our original Dataframe.
And we just say DTR, that's our
DecisionTreeRegressor model.fit, passing that training data,
and that one line of code we'll train
our decision tree model using that set of training data.
Very simple, right?
All right, so now that we have our model trained,
we can use it to make predictions.
We will call a model.transform passing in our test data,
and then we'll catch those results,
and call it full predictions.
So now we have a set of predictions for our test Dataset
of what our model says the price of unit area
should be given the house age, distance to MRT,
and number of convenience stores in that test Dataset.
So now we can extract both the predictions,
and the correct labels so we can print them out,
and compare them to each other.
This is kind of similar to the previous script.
So in this one, we're just going to convert it back
to an RDD to make that a little bit simpler
because extracting data out of a Dataframe
can get a little bit complicated.
RDD's are a little bit easier
to deal with from that standpoint.
So we extract our predictions from the prediction column,
and we extract our labels from the price
of unit area column, and we can compare the two.
So we zip them together based on the labels,
collect them back to our script,
and we iterate through each prediction and print them out.
When we're done we stop the session, and we're done.
Now again in the real world,
you probably wouldn't just be printing out
the original and predictive values.
You'd probably be comparing them together
on a more mathematical basis.
But again, this is not a machine learning course.
So I'm going to spare you all that
because I don't want to befuddle you too much
if that's not what you're here for.
let's run it and see what happens.
So I'll change my directory
to where my course materials are.
And we'll kick that off with
C spark bin sparked dash submit.
And the name of this script is realestate. PY.
Off it goes.
As always, it'll take a few seconds to spin up,
but once it does, it should make short work of this data.
It's not a very big Dataset, so it's not too challenging.
I do find decision trees fascinating as an aside,
they have to really understand what entropy really means
in order to understand how a decision tree works.
And that's kind of a cool insight to have.
But I digress, we have results. Let's look at them.
So it's kind of a mixed bag as before, you know.
Well, I mean, look at this one,
like the actual prediction was 39,
the real value was 61.5, 22 versus 62.
These aren't great results.
I don't think just by eyeballing it.
Again, there are a mathematical ways of measuring precisely
just how good this model is, but just by looking at it,
sometimes it did all right, sometimes not so much.
I'm sure there's a lot more that goes into the value
of a house than just how far it is
to the nearest transport station,
and how many convenience stores are nearby.
Those are probably interesting signals,
but clearly it's not enough to really describe the problem,
but the important thing is that it worked.
So there you have an example
of using a decision tree in Apache Spark.
And again, the cool thing is that
you could apply this to a massive Dataset,
and crunch that across an entire cluster.
Like I said, these entries are kind of cool these days.
Although the results here were kind of lackluster,
they can produce really good results
in a very simple manner.
And again, it saves you all the trouble of trying to scale
all that data down because it actually deals
with feature data in different scales pretty well.
So there you have it,
Spark ML, and you had a little exercise there
to get some practice with it.
Hope you got your feet wet with machine learning,
and how to use it in Apache Spark.
It's a very powerful capability that spark offers.
So remember, it's there, it's a good tool to have.