So let's introduce
Spark's machine learning library,
which has the creative name of ML
and to illustrate its usage,
we'll actually generate some movie recommendations
using it's a built in recommendation algorithm called ALS.
So a little bit about ML at a higher level.
It has a lot of capabilities.
You are limited to the algorithms
that provides out of the box,
but it's a pretty wide set of algorithms.
So for pretty much anything you'd wanna do,
short of neural networks, it's probably in there.
We have a Term Frequency and Inverse Document Frequency.
So if you're building a search engine,
that's a useful capability to have.
It has some basic statistical functions you can apply.
It can do regressions, both linear and logistics.
So whether you need to predict a number
or a category or a true false kind of a thing,
it can apply regression model
and sometimes simple models like that
are all you need for fancier stuff.
It has support vector machines.
Naive Bayes.
You know, you see that in a lot of
spam classifying examples out there.
Decision trees.
That's also a powerful technique for classification
and also for regression.
K-Means clustering, for clustering data together.
Principal component analysis, singular value decomposition.
You know, these are dimensionality reduction techniques
and finally the one we're gonna play with first,
Recommendations using Alternating Least Squares.
And some of these terms may make no sense to you at all
if you have no background in Machine Learning,
but if you do, they're there for you.
This is not a machine learning course though.
So I'm not really gonna get into the weeds
of what these all are,
but if you do need to apply Machine Learning
to massive data sets, you just need to know
that Spark has ways of doing it for most
of the most popular algorithms out there.
And that's really cool
because a lot of these algorithms
really weren't developed with parallelization in mind.
And the fact that Spark has come up with clever ways
of actually distributing these algorithms
across an entire cluster is really, really useful.
So ML uses data frames as its primary API.
There was an earlier API called MLLib.
It's still in Spark, but it's being deprecated
as of Spark 3, so eventually they will be getting rid of it.
And I've already noticed that some things
in MLLib don't really work the same way they used to
in Spark 3, so you definitely wanna be moving
to the new ML library if you can.
Previously it used RDD's
and some specialized data structures,
but these days you just use data frames for everything.
And this is handy because it means you
can create a Dataframe and SparkSQL,
or maybe even like do stuff with it in Spark streaming
or structured streaming and pass that
into the ML library, using the same API.
So it allows for more interoperability
between the different components of Spark.
If you wanna more depth, there is a nice book out there
from O'Reilly called "Advanced Analytics with Spark"
I don't get anything from it.
I didn't write it, but it is useful in learning how
to apply Machine Learning on Spark
and giving you more of an introduction
into what these algorithms do.
Sadly that was originally written
with the original MLLib library,
and they have actually updated it
to use the new ML library since then.
So make sure you get the second edition
if you get that book.
There are examples provided with the Spark SDK itself
that will provide you with some general guidance
on how to use these algorithms.
Often there's a lot of little nuances
in how to prepare the data that you feed into these models.
And it's not really documented anywhere except
in the examples, so if you are gonna try using some
of these algorithms on your own,
make sure you refer to the examples first.
And for the algorithms themselves,
there is no shortage for Machine Learning courses out there.
I have my own out there too, if you wanna check it out,
cough, cough.
So lots of ways to learn about Machine Learning and Spark.
So using it is actually really simple
and that's kind of the dirty little secret
of Machine Learning in general.
A lot of these algorithms are kind of black boxes
and it's just a matter of feeding it data
in the format that it expects
and feeding a quality data,
that's actually the hard part
and setting the appropriate knobs
and dials on those algorithms.
So we call those hyper parameters.
We'll see an example of that here.
But actually building a model and making predictions
from that model is usually pretty simple.
And what's even better is that because
all of these models basically have the same job
of applying some sort of learning to a set of data
and making predictions based on that data.
Often they have pretty much the same API.
So using different models
is actually really straightforward.
They all use kind of the same approach.
So for example, let's say we wanna make
some movie recommendations, which we're about to do,
the core of that is just really these three lines of code.
So we can read in our ratings data
that we wanna train it with.
So in this case, we're loading up that ml-100k data set
that we've looked at several times earlier in this course.
That's just a data set of 100,000 user ratings
of different movies.
As long as you've loaded that up in some sort of schema
that makes sense, we can just pass that
into the ALS model as you'll see here.
So, we create a new ALS model by just saying ALS
and max iterations and regularization parameter
are both what we call hyper parameters.
So another dirty little secret of Machine Learning
in general, is that most of the work,
well, I wouldn't say most of the workout,
a lot of the work is in what we call hyper parameter tuning.
And a lot of that is just trial and error.
There's usually not a lot of good guidance
as to what to set for the actual values,
for things like max iterations or regularization parameters
to get the best results.
What people often do is they just run
this algorithm repeatedly, trying out different values
until they converge on the set of values
that provide the best results for their dataset.
So yeah, a lot of ML is just trial and error
and that's kind of a, you know, something people
don't really appreciate very much.
Beyond that we just tell it what the column names are
for the userIDs and for the itemIDs
and for the ratings.
So whatever your Dataframe format may be,
as long as you have a column for userIDs,
you have a column for movieIDs
and you have a column for ratings,
you can just pass those in as parameters
to set user calls, set item call and set rating call.
And at that point you have a model object
that you can train, and to do that you just call fit on it,
passing in that Dataframe of the training data.
And at that point you can use that model
to predict how much a user might like a movie
that they haven't even seen yet.
It's just that easy.
So let's jump to the code and see how it works.
So let's introduce
Spark's machine learning library,
which has the creative name of ML.
And to illustrate its usage,
we'll actually generate some movie recommendations
using it's a built in recommendation algorithm called ALS.
So a little bit about ML at a higher level.
It has a lot of capabilities.
You are limited to the algorithms
that provides out of the box,
but it's a pretty wide set of algorithms.
So for pretty much anything you'd wanna do,
short of neural networks, it's probably in there.
We have a Term Frequency and Inverse Document Frequency.
So if you're building a search engine,
that's a useful capability to have.
It has some basic statistical functions you can apply.
It can do regressions, both linear and logistics.
So whether you need to predict a number
or a category or a true false kind of a thing,
it can apply regression model
and sometimes simple models like that
are all you need for fancier stuff.
It has support vector machines.
Naive Bayes.
You know, you see that in a lot of
spam classifying examples out there.
Decision trees.
That's also a powerful technique for classification
and also for regression.
K-Means clustering, for clustering data together.
Principal component analysis, singular value decomposition.
You know, these are dimensionality reduction techniques
and finally the one we're gonna play with first,
Recommendations using Alternating Least Squares.
And some of these terms may make no sense to you at all
if you have no background in Machine Learning,
but if you do, they're there for you.
This is not a machine learning course though.
So I'm not really gonna get into the weeds
of what these all are,
but if you do need to apply Machine Learning
to massive data sets, you just need to know
that Spark has ways of doing it for most
of the most popular algorithms out there.
And that's really cool
because a lot of these algorithms
really weren't developed with parallelization in mind.
And the fact that Spark has come up with clever ways
of actually distributing these algorithms
across an entire cluster is really, really useful.
So ML uses data frames as its primary API.
There was an earlier API called MLLib.
It's still in Spark, but it's being deprecated
as of Spark 3, so eventually they will be getting rid of it.
And I've already noticed that some things
in MLLib don't really work the same way they used to
in Spark 3, so you definitely wanna be moving
to the new ML library if you can.
Previously it used RDD's
and some specialized data structures,
but these days you just use data frames for everything.
And this is handy because it means you
can create a Dataframe and SparkSQL,
or maybe even like do stuff with it in Spark streaming
or structured streaming and pass that
into the ML library, using the same API.
So it allows for more interoperability
between the different components of Spark.
If you wanna more depth, there is a nice book out there
from O'Reilly called "Advanced Analytics with Spark"
I don't get anything from it.
I didn't write it, but it is useful in learning how
to apply Machine Learning on Spark
and giving you more of an introduction
into what these algorithms do.
Sadly that was originally written
with the original MLLib library,
and they have actually updated it
to use the new ML library since then.
So make sure you get the second edition
if you get that book.
There are examples provided with the Spark SDK itself
that will provide you with some general guidance
on how to use these algorithms.
Often there's a lot of little nuances
in how to prepare the data that you feed into these models.
And it's not really documented anywhere except
in the examples, so if you are gonna try using some
of these algorithms on your own,
make sure you refer to the examples first.
And for the algorithms themselves,
there is no shortage for Machine Learning courses out there.
I have my own out there too, if you wanna check it out,
cough, cough.
So lots of ways to learn about Machine Learning and Spark.
So using it is actually really simple
and that's kind of the dirty little secret
of Machine Learning in general.
A lot of these algorithms are kind of black boxes
and it's just a matter of feeding it data
in the format that it expects
and feeding a quality data,
that's actually the hard part
and setting the appropriate knobs
and dials on those algorithms.
So we call those hyper parameters.
We'll see an example of that here.
But actually building a model and making predictions
from that model is usually pretty simple.
And what's even better is that because
all of these models basically have the same job
of applying some sort of learning to a set of data
and making predictions based on that data.
Often they have pretty much the same API.
So using different models
is actually really straightforward.
They all use kind of the same approach.
So for example, let's say we wanna make
some movie recommendations, which we're about to do,
the core of that is just really these three lines of code.
So we can read in our ratings data
that we wanna train it with.
So in this case, we're loading up that ml-100k data set
that we've looked at several times earlier in this course.
That's just a data set of 100,000 user ratings
of different movies.
As long as you've loaded that up in some sort of schema
that makes sense, we can just pass that
into the ALS model as you'll see here.
So, we create a new ALS model by just saying ALS
and max iterations and regularization parameter
are both what we call hyper parameters.
So another dirty little secret of Machine Learning
in general, is that most of the work,
well, I wouldn't say most of the workout,
a lot of the work is in what we call hyper parameter tuning.
And a lot of that is just trial and error.
There's usually not a lot of good guidance
as to what to set for the actual values,
for things like max iterations or regularization parameters
to get the best results.
What people often do is they just run
this algorithm repeatedly, trying out different values
until they converge on the set of values
that provide the best results for their dataset.
So yeah, a lot of ML is just trial and error
and that's kind of a, you know, something people
don't really appreciate very much.
Beyond that we just tell it what the column names are
for the userIDs and for the itemIDs
and for the ratings.
So whatever your Dataframe format may be,
as long as you have a column for userIDs,
you have a column for movieIDs
and you have a column for ratings,
you can just pass those in as parameters
to set user calls, set item call and set rating call.
And at that point you have a model object
that you can train, and to do that you just call fit on it,
passing in that Dataframe of the training data.
And at that point you can use that model
to predict how much a user might like a movie
that they haven't even seen yet.
It's just that easy.
So let's jump to the code and see how it works.