So let's do another machine
learning exercise with spark.
And this is a fun one,
because we're going
to be using some real data again,
we're going to predict real estate values,
using some real, real estate data from Taiwan,
using decision trees this time,
and Patrice Spark.
A little bit the credit to the data set
that we're using,
you'll find it
in the realestate.csv file,
in your course materials.
And it comes from the UCI data repository.
You'll find this as a good resource,
for finding publicly available data sets
for playing around with,
for machine learning purposes.
I found this just by searching for a data sets,
that were suitable for regression problems.
So that's what we're trying
to show you here.
The data itself looks like this,
viewed in a Excel format at least.
So you can see that for every row
of our data here,
we have a transaction date,
a house age,
distance to MRT.
That's actually distance
to the nearest public transportation system terminal.
The number of nearby convenience stores,
the latitude and longitude of the house
and the price per unit area of that,
that house sold for.
Now again, this is coming from Taiwan
from a new Taipei city,
I think it is so.
If you're not from there,
don't expect to understand the local currency,
or the quirks of the local
real estate market there.
The point though,
is that you want to predict
the price per unit
area, based on just the house age,
the distance to public transportation,
and the number of nearby convenience stores.
One would think there would be a lot more
that goes into the price of a house than that,
but this is what we have to work with.
So let's see what you can do with it.
Your strategy, is to use a decision tree regressor,
instead of a linear regression model here,
and they work pretty much the same way.
It shouldn't be too hard.
The reason that we're going
with the decision tree regressor
is just to save you some work,
because decision trees can handle data
in different scales better.
So you don't have to worry about, scaling all
of your input data down, all
of your feature data down
to the same range,
and then scaling it back up again
When you're done.
If this were a machine learning course,
I might make you do that,
but it's not.
So, I'm not gonna make you
waste your time,
just use the decision tree,
and be done with it.
And honestly, a little bit of an aside here,
decision trees are kind
of the new hotness.
There's something called XG boost,
which is gradient boosted decision trees,
which is sort of a variation on decision trees,
that uses multiple decision trees
to build upon each other.
And that is actually one
of the most powerful machine
learning algorithms out there right now.
So decision trees are a powerful tool regardless.
So, start with a copy
of the spark-linear-regression script there,
that's going to be a good thing to start from,
but it's gotta be a little bit easier,
because we have a header row this time.
So you don't need a hard code,
a scheme of reading the data file.
You don't have to do all that nonsense
of converting it to an RDD
and applying a map function to it.
Granted we could have handled
that previous example by having an explicit schema
and reading it in as a CSV,
but I just want to show you a different way
to do it in that last example,
by mixing and matching RTDs
and data frames.
But for this one,
there's no need to use
to RTDs at all.
We have a hetero,
so you can import that,
CSV file directly, as a data frame
without much trouble. So, just do that.
Few useful snippets of code
as you get started.
First of all,
you can have multiple input columns
and what we call a VectorAssembler.
So as you, after you import that raw data frame
from the source data,
and alternate way of building that
into the format that the decision tree regressor expects,
is by using something called a VectorAssembler.
So, before we had this RDD that we used to
with a map function to transform that,
into the format that
our linear regression model expected,
but an easier way, is actually to use a VectorAssembler.
So you'll probably want to take note of
this little syntax here,
or at least remember in the back of your head,
to look up a VectorAssembler,
because it's going to help you complete this task.
The format is something like this.
You just save VectorAssembler.setinputCols,
and you just give it a list of the
input columns that you want to assemble
as your features.
And then you just say assembler.transform,
passing in your original data frame,
load it up from that CSV file.
And furthermore, you can select the label column name,
and then the features.
The features will be sort of that,
that vector of feature datam.
So in the end,
you're going to have two columns,
that you've passed
into the decision tree regressor,
the first column will be your label,
which you can name whatever you want.
And the second will be a vector of features.
Just kind like the last one,
but we're doing it in a bit more straightforward
of a manner this time, by using a VectorAssembler,
instead of using a map function on an RDD.
And again, remember because we do have a header row,
you can load that data more easily directly
into a data frame,
just by using a data option header true,
and option in first schema true.
When you read that, in from the spark session interface,
as opposed to the spark context interface.
And again, we're going to use
the decision tree regressor, instead
of the linear regression model,
works the same way though.
One nice thing is that,
you can just omit the hyperparameters
on the decision tree regressor.
So, the same hyperparameters
that we specified for the linear regression model,
aren't going to be the same
as we use under the decision
to treat your aggressor.
It has its own hyperparameters,
but don't worry about that for now.
Just leave them unspecified,
and it will still work.
You will, however,
have to call .setlabelCol,
on their model, that will allow you
to specify the name of the label column,
assuming that it's name is not just label,
which is the default.
So with that good luck,
and see if you can get through that.
I did leave a little bit more work for you
to do on this one,
so it's not going to be a simple matter
of just modifying that previous example.
There's a little bit more involved,
a work to be done here,
but that's the point we want
to work you up to, developing these things
on your own at the end of the day.
So have at it,
and in the next lecture,
we'll take a look at my solution
to the problem.