Next let's briefly talk about GraphX.
this is one of the other main blocks that sit on top of Spark core -
so we should talk about it. Now, when we talk about GraphX and graph processing we're not talking about
line charts and pie charts and things like that,
we're talking about graphs in the computer science sense.
So things like social networks where you have these nodes that represent people, and they're interconnected
by their relationships,
that's the kind of graph that we're talking about here.
Kind of like our social network of superheroes that we had,
you know, remember we had the example of Marvel superheroes that were connected by what comics they appeared
together in -
that's an example of a graph.
Now the thing with GraphX is that it's currently only available in the Scala API, Python support doesn't
really seem to be coming anytime soon, if at all. GraphX
quite honestly it's been kind of languishing for the past few years, it hasn't really caught on as
something that a lot of people are using,
so it hasn't gotten a lot of attention from the maintainers of the open source version of Apache Spark
and there are some third party packages out there that people seem to be leaning more toward than using
GraphX itself.
The thing is, it's only really useful for a few specific things
and this is probably part of why it hasn't really been adopted very much.
It wouldn't have actually helped us a whole lot with our degrees of separation example, for example.
You would think it would, you know, but it doesn't.
But it can do things like measure things like connectedness or degree distribution and average path
length and triangle counts.
Basically, these high level measures that describe the properties of a graph as a whole
and it can also join graphs together and transform them very quickly,
that's what it's all about, that's why you want to distribute this with Spark,
if you have two large graphs and you need to merge them together, GraphX is a good tool for doing that.
Under the hood,
it introduces a couple of new data types called a VertexRDD and EdgeRDD,
but otherwise, GraphX code looks like pretty much any other Spark code,
it's not really that unusual.
So if you do need to work with network analysis code and graphs of information like that, it might be
worth learning Scala and maybe, maybe picking up the Scala version of this course to get a hands on example
of using GraphX,
but as of now, in the world of Python Spark, it's not really something you can do, but you should at least
know what GraphX is -
because it is a component of spark itself and well, that's what it's all about.
Next let's briefly talk about GraphX,
This is one of the other main blocks that sit on top of Spark core,
so we should talk about it. Now, when we talk about GraphX and graph processing, we're not talking about
line charts and pie charts and things like that.
We're talking about graphs in the computer science sense.
So things like social networks where you have these nodes that represent people, and they're interconnected
by their relationships,
that's the kind of graph that we're talking about here.
Kind of like our social network of superheroes that we had.
You know, remember we had the example of Marvel superheroes that were connected by what comics they appeared
together in -
that's an example of a graph.
Now the thing with GraphX is, that it's currently only available in the Scala API, Python support doesn't
really seem to be coming anytime soon, if at all. GraphX
quite honestly it's been kind of languishing for the past few years, it hasn't really caught on as
something that a lot of people are using.
So it hasn't gotten a lot of attention from the maintainers of the open source version of Apache Spark,
and there are some third party packages out there that people seem to be leaning more toward than using
GraphX itself.
The thing is, it's only really useful for a few specific things,
and this is probably part of why it hasn't really been adopted very much.
It wouldn't have actually helped us a whole lot with our degrees of separation example, for example.
You would think it would, you know, but it doesn't.
But it can do things like, measure things like connectedness, or degree distribution, and average path
length, and triangle counts.
Basically, these high level measures that describe the properties of a graph as a whole.
And it can also join graphs together and transform them very quickly.
That's what it's all about, that's why you want to distribute this with Spark,
if you have two large graphs and you need to merge them together, GraphX is a good tool for doing that.
Under the hood,
it introduces a couple of new data types called a VertexRDD and EdgeRDD,
but otherwise, GraphX code looks like pretty much any other Spark code,
it's not really that unusual.
So if you do need to work with network analysis code and graphs of information like that, it might be
worth learning Scala, and maybe picking up the Scala version of this course to get a hands on example
of using GraphX,
but as of now, in the world of Python Spark, it's not really something you can do. But you should at least
know what GraphX is -
because it is a component of Spark itself. And well, that's what it's all about.