All right, I hope you had some success with that one more of a challenging exercise, but I think it
gave you enough hints to be successful.
So if you did have trouble with it or you want to verify how you went about it, let's compare your
results to mine.
So here's my top dash URL's script here that solves the problem.
And it is basically identical to the previous activity up to the point where we actually load up the
data frame and do stuff with it.
So we have the same regular expressions and we're using the same regular regular expressions to extract
the various fields of that access, log into a more structured format, into logs, D.F., into our
data frame there.
So let's pick up down here and see what's going on.
So the first thing I did that I mentioned was create this new column called Event Time.
That's equal to the current timestamp.
So that's going to be populated with the time at which this data was actually ingested.
And that is kind of a hack because we're using old access logs here instead of access logs that were
just freshly made in the real world, you probably wouldn't have to do this.
But now that we have that current event time column there, we can do stuff with it.
And here's that window operation that we talked about.
So, again, we wanted to set up a 30 second window with a 10 second slide interval.
And the format for this would look like this.
So we have a new endpoint counts data frame that's constructed with logs down two, which is just the
logs data frame with that extra event time column.
Add it in.
We call function window Funchal event time.
So that's going to be the time that we're windowing on with a 30 second window interval and a 10 second
slide interval.
And then the second argument for the group by function is just the endpoint column because we're trying
to group by you URLs.
And in the parlance of our code here, the actual URL is the endpoint.
So technically, you know, the format here is method that endpoint.
So it's going to be like get some URL in some situations, maybe that's not a URL, but for all intents
and purposes, for us it is.
Then we count them up.
So we're just trying to get the count of unique endpoints windowed by that 30 second and 10 second window
invalid slide interval based on the event time column.
Now that we have that, we can sort it and we just say order by Funchal, count in descending order
and then we just display the stream to the console.
And to do that, we just say sorted endpoints, count start right stream output mode, complete format,
console, query name counts, dot start.
So we're just giving that query a name called Counts and then start kicks that off.
So it will just start streaming that and running it forever until we actually stop our script.
So in going on in this line, it's worth unpacking a little bit here.
So again, we're setting up a new query named Accounts that will run forever until we stop it.
And that's going to just keep on writing to the stream in complete output mode, to the console the
results of sorted endpoint counts.
All right.
Now, the real world, you probably would not want to just write the output to the console.
You probably want to save it somewhere.
Right.
So instead of the format console, this might be going to a sequel database.
You might be getting story to a text file on a distributed file system somewhere, whatever.
But you can do all that stuff right here from right stream.
So if you just look up the documentation for right stream for Apache Spark, you'll see there's all
sorts of possibilities for where you can write it to.
So we just go ahead and run that awaiting termination.
We just say keep running that query forever until I stop it.
And when I finally do stop it, I will stop the session with sparked not stop.
So let's see if it works back to my anakonda prompt here and we will call Spark.
Oops, Sparks submits on top your URL Stoppie and we'll let that spin up.
Now it's not going to do anything at first because right now there's nothing in my logs folder and if
there is stuff in your logs folder from the previous activity, then it will go ahead and start to do
stuff right away.
But for me there isn't because I clean things up.
So let's just give that a chance to start.
I think it's probably running by now, so let's go ahead and put some laws in there for it to play with.
So I'm going to make three copies of my access log here to play with.
So I'm just going to control and paste, control and paste, whatever you want to do to copy that to
a couple of different file names.
So let's start by copying the access log into my logs folder here.
And you could do this from a terminal just using the CPP command, obviously, but I'm on windows,
so a little bit easier.
Let's wait for that to spin up, I can hear my CPU's fans spinning so I know it's doing something.
All right, so we can see our top yourself there and we actually have three different slight intervals
that we've had already.
Let's see if I can hit this again before 30 seconds are up.
Put that copy in there.
Spin it up again.
Not sure I timed that quick enough to actually see overlapping windows there.
Yeah, you can see that those those windows expired.
So I'm still seeing the same counts for every window there.
But feel free to play with this.
If you were able to get that quick enough, you should see that basically double for some windows in
cases where the windows overlap for different slide intervals.
But this is cool.
So you can see our data frame here where we're actually printing out that accumulation of different
slide intervals for a given 30 second window and giving you those top URLs for each window that encounters.
And we're seeing that Zemel, RBC and WP log in are actually the top URLs being hit.
Turns out that's because someone was actually trying to attack my website during this time.
Someone was actually trying to break into my site by hacking a vulnerability and WordPress and they
weren't able to do it, but they were able to slow down my website by hitting it this hard.
So this is kind of a real world example of where this sort of analysis in real time could alert me or
help me at least diagnose what's going on with my website while it was under attack.
So there you have it, spark streaming with windows and window intervals and slight intervals and a
little bit of an example of using structured streaming in a more complex manner.
And that's basically streaming and spark and structured streaming in a nutshell.
I mean, there are some more nuances we could cover.
And, you know, there's a whole other course on spark streaming, but that is definitely enough to
make you dangerous.
And the biggest use case is actually streaming an Apache log data like this.
So I think this will be a good, again, tool to have in your tool chest just by keeping the script
around for future reference.
So there you have sparks streaming.
Another thing you've learned.
All right, I hope you had some success with that one more of a challenging exercise, but I think it
gave you enough hints to be successful.
So if you did have trouble with it or you want to verify how you went about it, let's compare your
results to mine.
So here's my top dash URL's script here that solves the problem.
And it is basically identical to the previous activity, up to the point where we actually load up the
data frame and do stuff with it.
So we have the same regular expressions and we're using the same regular regular expressions to extract
the various fields of that access, log into a more structured format, into logs, D.F., into our
data frame there.
So let's pick up down here and see what's going on.
So the first thing I did that I mentioned was create this new column called Event Time.
That's equal to the current timestamp.
So that's going to be populated with the time at which this data was actually ingested.
And that is kind of a hack because we're using old access logs here instead of access logs that were
just freshly made in the real world, you probably wouldn't have to do this.
But now that we have that current event time column there, we can do stuff with it.
And here's that window operation that we talked about.
So, again, we wanted to set up a 30 second window with a 10 second slide interval.
And the format for this would look like this.
So we have a new endpoint counts data frame that's constructed with logs down two, which is just the
logs data frame with that extra event time column.
Add it in.
We call function window Funchal event time.
So that's going to be the time that we're windowing on with a 30 second window interval and a 10 second
slide interval.
And then the second argument for the group by function is just the endpoint column because we're trying
to group by you URLs.
And in the parlance of our code here, the actual URL is the endpoint.
So technically, you know, the format here is method that endpoint.
So it's going to be like get some URL in some situations, maybe that's not a URL, but for all intents
and purposes, for us it is.
Then we count them up.
So we're just trying to get the count of unique endpoints windowed by that 30 second and 10 second window
invalid slide interval based on the event time column.
Now that we have that, we can sort it and we just say order by Funchal, count in descending order
and then we just display the stream to the console.
And to do that, we just say sorted endpoints, count start right stream output mode, complete format,
console, query name counts, dot start.
So we're just giving that query a name called Counts and then start kicks that off.
So it will just start streaming that and running it forever until we actually stop our script.
So in going on in this line, it's worth unpacking a little bit here.
So again, we're setting up a new query named Accounts that will run forever until we stop it.
And that's going to just keep on writing to the stream in complete output mode, to the console the
results of sorted endpoint counts.
All right.
Now, the real world, you probably would not want to just write the output to the console.
You probably want to save it somewhere.
Right.
So instead of the format console, this might be going to a sequel database.
You might be getting story to a text file on a distributed file system somewhere, whatever.
But you can do all that stuff right here from right stream.
So if you just look up the documentation for right stream for Apache Spark, you'll see there's all
sorts of possibilities for where you can write it to.
So we just go ahead and run that awaiting termination.
We just say keep running that query forever until I stop it.
And when I finally do stop it, I will stop the session with sparked not stop.
So let's see if it works back to my anakonda prompt here and we will call Spark.
Oops, Sparks submits on top your URL Stoppie and we'll let that spin up.
Now it's not going to do anything at first because right now there's nothing in my logs folder and if
there is stuff in your logs folder from the previous activity, then it will go ahead and start to do
stuff right away.
But for me there isn't because I clean things up.
So let's just give that a chance to start.
I think it's probably running by now, so let's go ahead and put some laws in there for it to play with.
So I'm going to make three copies of my access log here to play with.
So I'm just going to control and paste, control and paste, whatever you want to do to copy that to
a couple of different file names.
So let's start by copying the access log into my logs folder here.
And you could do this from a terminal just using the CPP command, obviously, but I'm on windows,
so a little bit easier.
Let's wait for that to spin up, I can hear my CPU's fans spinning so I know it's doing something.
All right, so we can see our top yourself there and we actually have three different slight intervals
that we've had already.
Let's see if I can hit this again before 30 seconds are up.
Put that copy in there.
Spin it up again.
Not sure I timed that quick enough to actually see overlapping windows there.
Yeah, you can see that those those windows expired.
So I'm still seeing the same counts for every window there.
But feel free to play with this.
If you were able to get that quick enough, you should see that basically double for some windows in
cases where the windows overlap for different slide intervals.
But this is cool.
So you can see our data frame here where we're actually printing out that accumulation of different
slide intervals for a given 30 second window and giving you those top URLs for each window that encounters.
And we're seeing that Zemel, RBC and WP log in are actually the top URLs being hit.
Turns out that's because someone was actually trying to attack my website during this time.
Someone was actually trying to break into my site by hacking a vulnerability and WordPress and they
weren't able to do it, but they were able to slow down my website by hitting it this hard.
So this is kind of a real world example of where this sort of analysis in real time could alert me or
help me at least diagnose what's going on with my website while it was under attack.
So there you have it, spark streaming with windows and window intervals and slight intervals and a
little bit of an example of using structured streaming in a more complex manner.
And that's basically streaming and spark and structured streaming in a nutshell.
I mean, there are some more nuances we could cover.
And, you know, there's a whole other course on spark streaming, but that is definitely enough to
make you dangerous.
And the biggest use case is actually streaming an Apache log data like this.
So I think this will be a good, again, tool to have in your tool chest just by keeping the script
around for future reference.
So there you have sparks streaming.
Another thing you've learned.