So spark streaming and structured streaming is definitely an important thing to know with Apache
Spark its a very popular thing to do, especially when you're investing log data in real time.
So I'm going to give you a chance to actually practice this yourself.
Your exercise this time will be to use the same access log that we used in the previous activity.
But I want you to stream the top URLs seen within the past 30 seconds.
OK, so that's a little bit of a twist on things.
Now, to get that past 30 seconds bid as opposed to since the beginning of time, you need to understand
something called windowing.
Now, a windowed operation.
We talked about this with D streams with this also applies to structured streaming.
It looks back over some period of time.
So, for example, you could consider only events that happened in the past 10 minutes.
In that case, 10 minutes would be the window.
There's also a concept of a slide interview and that defines how often you're evaluating a window.
So, for example, you could have a ten minute window and a slide interval of five minutes.
So every five minutes we would look at the current 10 minute interval of the window and re-evaluate
that.
So the slide is just how often do we re-evaluate things and start reevaluating our windows.
And the window time is that period at which we analyze data within.
It makes more sense with an example.
So this is coming straight from the Apache Spark documentation here, but it's a good illustrative example.
So imagine you have a stream of input data that just has a stream of animal names coming in, cats and
dogs and owls and whatnot.
So imagine, if you will, we start the stream at 12 o'clock and at 12 02 we get cat dog and a 12 or
three we got dog, dog.
So let's imagine, if you will, that we have 10 minute windows and we have a five minute slide like
we talked about.
So the first slide rule that will hit will be 12:05, but that will reside within our first 10 minute
window that runs from 12 o'clock to 12:10.
So a 12:05 our slide
interval gets hit and we say, OK, within this 10 minute window that I'm in, what's our current status?
And at this point, we have one cat and three dogs that have been received so far, 12:07.
We see an owl and a cat.
So a 12:10, another slight interval gets hit and we're still in that 12 o'clock to 12:10 window
here.
But now we have more data within that window that's come in.
So now we have two cats, three dogs and one owl.
But we're also within another new window that goes from 12:05 to 12:15.
And in that window, we just have one cat and one owl.
Now, keep in mind, these results are stored within a data frame.
So the way structured streaming works again is that we just have this data frame that keeps growing
forever.
And that's true with Windows as well.
So we're going to have this growing data frame that consists of every possible window with every possible
slight interval over time, and it just keeps piling up forever and forever.
All right.
Moving on with the example, say, a 12:11 and 12:13, we get a dog and an owl.
Our next slide interval hits a 12:15.
And now we have three windows that we've looked at, 12 o'clock to 12:10, 12:05 to 12:15 and
12:10 to 12: 20.
And at this point, you can see that we've added in that extra dog and owl to both the 12: 05 to
12:15 window and also to the new 12:10 to 12:20 window that's just starting to take shape.
So hopefully that makes it a little bit more clear of how windows work and how slight intervals work
and how they interact with each other.
Your challenge is to apply that to this problem.
A little bit of a snippet of how that would work in code.
So if you wanted to implement that previous example with a ten minute window and a five minute slide
duration, the code itself might look something like this.
We might be doing something like data set, not group by func dot window.
We're going to find that window here.
Func dot col, time stamp column name, whatever it is that you're looking at for the time stamp that you're
basing those windows on, window duration equals whatever it is, duration equals whatever it is.
So that window scale function can be used to actually do windowed streaming operations within a data
frame.
And furthermore, we have to pass in the column that we're grouping by,that's just another parameter
for the group by function, not the window function there.
But you can see there the syntax and you'll want to make note of this because you're going to need that
in this exercise.
So again, your challenge here is to modify the structured streaming script.
Why is that hard to say that we did in the previous activity to keep track of the most viewed URLs in
our logs.
And normally that would be easy.
But that window twist is going to make it a little bit more challenging for you.
And I want you to compute this with a 30 second window, with a 10 second slide, some useful snippets
of code if you want to cheat a little bit.
First of all, here's the group by and window format that you'll need to set that up.
And another problem is going to be that we don't really have a useful timestamp function in that access
log data.
This is a old access log from years ago.
So you don't want to be using that as what, your windowing by.
Right.
So instead we can fabricate a new column called Event Time that contains the current timestamp.
So that will populate that eventTime column with whatever time that log data was ingested in.
So that will be more useful for experimentation purposes.
Normally, if you're actually streaming in data in real time, you'll have you'll be able to use whatever
time is in the logs.
But in this case, since we're using old logs, we have to fudge things a little bit.
So you'll find that line of code quite useful for fabricating an event time column that you can then
use on that window function.
And finally, when you're done, you'll want to order the endpoint counts by the count column and dot
descending is the format for doing that in descending order.
So I don't think we've covered that before.
So have at it guys.
And again, we've kind of worked you up to more challenging examples here.
You will need to do a little bit more research, a little bit more creative thinking for this one than
before, but I think you're up to it.
So have a go at it and we'll come back in the next lecture and I'll show you my solution.