So let's go ahead and walk through an example of using Spark streaming within Python here, and within
your course materials you should have a couple of things associated with this example,
one is the structured-streaming.py script that we're looking at right now and also the
access_log.txt file.
This is an actual Apache access log from one of the Web sites that I run.
So what we're going to do is write a little script here that monitors a directory that has access logs
being dumped into it.
This is something you might actually see in the real world on a real web server right.
And just keep monitoring that for new access logs and we want to keep a running count of how many status
codes appear over time as this new log data is being adjusted.
And this will let us do things like alert if we're seeing too many error codes are being generated by
the server for example.
So let's take a look through the actual script here and walk through it real quickly.
So we start off by importing the various packages we need including SparkContext and also from pyspark.streaming,
streaming context as well.
And we're also going to import some functions for doing regular expressions so we can actually parse
our Apache access logs into something more structured.
We start by creating our Spark session.
Nothing too special here we just call SparkSession.builder to do that with the following configuration
options.
This config is only necessary on windows by the way.
Make sure you have a C temp directory created already if you don't already.
And that's just to work around an issue on Windows.
You'll find often that Windows support is kind of an afterthought with Spark.
Sometimes things don't quite work properly on windows and this is a workaround for one of those things.
We're gonna call the name StructuredStreaming and we'll call it getOrCreate to either create a new
session or reuse an existing one.
And this is important because we as we mentioned Spark can do check points.
So if you did actually terminate this thing unexpectedly get or create could actually recreate the previous
Spark session based on that checkpoint of data that had in place before.
So if it did stop unexpectedly you could resume it by just running it again.
Very nice feature, Sparks Streaming.
So what we're gonna do is call spark.readStream.text("logs") what this does is create a new stream
of data coming from the logs directory here on my file system.
So it's just gonna sit there looking at our logs directory waiting for new text files to be dumped into
it and it will stream that new data as it's found into access lines.
Now one thing that's worth noting is that during development I could just say spark.read instead
of readStream and write all the same code just using a static data frame instead of a streaming one.
So again it's very useful for development purposes where you can just switch from a static data frame
to a streaming one by just changing read to readStream when you're done.
So that does make life a little bit simpler for testing and development.
Once we have that we need to convert this into a data frame that has the structure that we want.
So this is problematic.
Like right now we just have individual lines from our access log and they're kind of messy to look at
if we look at an example.
Let's go back to our materials here and open up the access logs text file just to see what we're up
against.
So this is what an Apache axis log looks like.
Basically it starts with an IP address of the requester it has a timestamp,
it has the actual request that was made of HTTP which is usually getSomeURL over this
protocol.
And then we have the status code.
So two hundred indicates success and a bunch of other stuff like "refers" and things like that.
So we need to parse these lines out into their structure.
So that's what the following code does.
Close out of this. I don't want to get into the details of regular expressions.
I mean that will be a whole course of itself.
But just take it on faith that what this code does is parse out each individual log line and break it
up into its individual components.
So by saying accessLines.select with all these regular expressions, we're saying use these patterns
to match patterns in that access log line to extract the hosts, the timestamp, the method, the endpoint, the
protocol, the status code, and the content size based on these patterns that we've defined here.
And as we do that we're going to generate a new data frame called logsDF that contains these host
timestamp method et cetera aliases as column names.
So at that point we can just refer to this data frame as we would any data frame,
the only difference is that because it's streaming we're appending new information to it over time continuously.
So, pretty cool how that works. Now that we have the data frame handy we can just say group that data
frame by the status code and keep it running CAF read status code.
So with one line of code we said keep track of everything by status code with the "group by" command and
keep them up over time.
So it's a very SQL style format there,
in fact you could just make that a SQL command if you preferred.
Once we have that defined we basically told it what we wanted to do, we want it to count up status
codes over time.
We just kick it off with this line here.
We say take that status counts data frame that we've defined, our final results there, and call write
stream to dump the results somewhere.
So in this case we're just gonna dump the complete output to the console and we're gonna have that query
a name called "counts" and calls "start" to actually kick it off.
So that will actually start our structured streaming application, where we have this status counts data
frame that just keeps expanding and changing over time based on what status codes that it sees coming
in, and we'll just run that forever until termination is detected,
and at that point we have to cleanly shut down our Sparks session to let things know that it shut down
successfully.
We don't need to like recover that from a snapshot later on.
So let's see if it works.
So we'll go back to our Canopy command prompt.
Actually already have one open here so I'm just gonna go back to it and we will type in
spark-submit structured-streaming.py
but before you hit enter make sure you have a log structure for it to monitor or else the code won't
work.
So back to our course materials here.
I already have a logs directory here that's created, there should be nothing in it at this point
but if you need to create a logs directory first please take care of that right now.
Once we have a log structure in place we can actually kick this off.
So let's do so.
Give that chance to spin up and just get Spark started and let's get some data to actually play with.
So let's put this off to the side here.
And what I'm going to do is take that access log.txt file, hit CTRL+C to copy it, and let's
go to our logs directory and paste it in.
And that should trigger our application to do something, it's going to say "oh this logs directory that
I'm monitoring has some new information in it,
let's process it."
So give it a few seconds to actually pick that up.
And there we have our first batch of information there, so we can see that we have quite a few five hundreds
there.
So turns out something is actually going wrong there but that's successfully counting up the number of
status codes within this entire access log file here and it's quite a bit of information actually.
We've got about 10 k of information there.
Let's go ahead and see if we get further data here just to demonstrate that it is in fact streaming.
So let's go back to our course materials here and let's rename access_log.txt to something else,
underscore one perhaps, and copy that new file, which is really a copy of the original one, into our logs
directory, and what I would expect to see is all of these counts to double right.
Because now we've added the same information in twice but we're still monitoring the stream of information.
So it should say "hey I just saw some new information come into my logs directory,
I better go process it". And there it is.
And sure enough everything is double what it was before.
So hey structured streaming actually works.
We just have this giant data frame keeping track of all the information coming in and distilling it
down to this account data frame that's keeping track of all the different status codes and how often
they've appeared over time.
So again very easy very clean API and you can kind of see why they're pushing people in this direction
as opposed to Dstreams.
Not only is it a cleaner API for working with, it also makes development easier,
and it also increases in operability with other parts of Spark and beyond that it's real time streaming
or about as near real time as you can get anyway.
It's not dealing with discrete batches anymore.
It's really streaming.
So cool stuff, that is Spark Streaming in action within Python.
There's a whole lot more to Spark Streaming to explore, in fact I have a whole other course on it, but
that should give you a feel of how it all works and a nice little working example here with Sparks Streaming
within Python.
It turns out the examples that are included in the Python SDK currently don't actually include a Spark
Streaming example so, you might want to keep this one around.
It could be a handy reference for you. When you're done just hit CTRL+C here and terminate that.
You'll have to terminate it possibly two or more times for reach core that's running and then you're done.