So we've talked about Spark Core and AML lib and also Sparks SQL which are to the boxes built on top
of Spark Core.
Let's talk about those other two boxes Spark Streaming and GraphX.
We'll start with Spark Streaming that's definitely the bigger of the two and the one that's more widely
used Spark Streaming is used for analyzing continual streams of data.
So sometimes you don't just have this big corpus of data just sitting there that you want to analyze
as a big batch, you have a continual stream of data that's always coming in all the time.
And a common example of that is the problem of processing log data that's being generated by a Web site
or a server somewhere, where that server just keeps on generating log data forever and you need to monitor
that thing in real time or near real time at least. For example maybe you need to keep a watch on error
codes that are being generated and you want to generate some sort of an alarm or pay somebody or alert
somebody when things go wrong, Sparks Streaming can do that.
The idea is to aggregate and analyze data as it's being streamed in at some given interval, and you can
take that data from pretty much anywhere,
I mean at a low level you can listen to data that's just fed in on some arbitrary port.
So if it can talk to TCP you can feed it into Sparks Streaming. But you can also deal with integrations
with specific systems to make things a little bit easier.
For example Amazon Kinesis or listening to data that's being dropped in an HDFS file system or data
that's being generated by Kafka or Flume and other systems.
These things all have APIs and libraries that you can use to talk to them directly and consume that
data into Sparks Streaming, crunch that data on your Spark cluster and then take the results and feed
it off to another stream or act on it in some way stored in a database whatever you want to do. It also
has some nice features for a fault tolerance,
for example it has a check pointing feature that will continually store its current state to disk periodically.
So that way if your stream goes down or something goes wrong with the entire system, it can pick up where
it left off automatically the next time you get it running again,
so that's a good feature of Spark Streaming.
These are complicated systems that involve you know multiple systems that involve clusters of their
own.
So there's a lot that can go wrong so that's an important feature to have. There's a couple of ways of
doing Spark Streaming.
The old way that sort of a historical way of doing it is using what we call a Dstream object.
And the idea of a Dstream is that your stream is broken up into distinct RDD's.
So technically it's not a real time stream of information with a Dstream, you're getting what we call
micro batches, just little snapshots of each chunk of data that's coming in and you deal with each chunk
at a time as a distinct RDD.
A simple example of that is here on the slide,
so this is a streaming word count example that comes straight out of the examples that ship with the
Spark SDK.
You start with the Spark context and from there you can create a streaming context built on top of that
Spark context.
So the parameters on the first line indicate that we're creating a streaming context from a Spark context
named sc and the 1 means that we want to break that up into one second chunk.
So we're gonna be taking one second periods of that data, making individual RDD's out of each one second
worth of data and then processing those RDD's individually.
So at this point we're assuming that we're dealing with an individual RDD,
and we're gonna call an RDD call line, it's going to represent a 1 second snapshot of a text file stream
coming from the books directory.
So text file stream just listens to a directory somewhere in a file system, in this case maybe it's an
HDFS file system where it has a directory called Books and we'll just sit there monitoring that books
directory looking for new data being dumped into it over time, as new data comes in within each one second
intervals will process the data that it sees within that one second and feed that back into your lines
RDD here.
From there we can process it.
So this line here is just some Python Spark code to count up the number of occurrences of each word
within that RDD.
So we start off with a lambda function that just splits each line in to individual words based on the
space character.
We then map that to a count,
so we have a mapping of each individual word to the number 1 and then we just add up all those ones
together to get a final count of each word with reduced by key.
So that's just keeping a count of all the individual words how often they appear within that RDD,
we then print out the results and that's it.
So those four lines of code are pretty much all you need to monitor a directory and keep a running count
of how many words appear within a given one second increment of information.
Once you have that you do need to kick off the job explicitly.
You just need to call scc.start to kick off monitoring that books folder there and actually start
the stream and then you call awaitTermination to just say go and run this repeatedly forever until
I say stop.
That's all there is to it.
So Dstreams again are near real time,
there they're a micro batch API where we're dealing with chunks of data being streamed and continuously
but they're not it's not technically real time streaming.
OK.
So some people find that a little bit off putting but it's kind of hard to find an application where
a 1 second delay is really a big deal.
So in a lot of cases a Dstream is a perfectly legitimate way to go.
Totally fine.
And actually the examples that ship with Spark itself for Python streaming all use this Dstream API still.
So you know even though there is a newer version- a newer API that we're going to look at shortly, they
still seem to be focusing on this in the Python world. now remember your RDD's with the Dstream only contain
that one little chunk of incoming data.
Now there are ways to aggregate data across multiple RDD's, these multiple chunks and actually keep
track of things over time.
We have something called windowed operations where you can actually combine results from multiple batches
over some sliding time window. So there are these functions like window and reduce by window and reduce
by key n window that you could use to do that word count example over a sliding window say the past
hours worth of data or the past day's worth of data whatever you want whenever window of time you want.
So you can do that pretty easily with Dstreams.
You can also maintain any arbitrary state you want across these different batches that come in from
your streaming data, updateStateByKey is what lets you do that.
That just lets you keep track of some sort of state, some arbitrary information across many batches as
time goes on.
So for example if you wanted to keep a running count of some advent or like the total number of lines
that you've processed since the beginning of the stream, you could use updateStateByKey to do that.
And if you want to see an example of that in action just navigate into the Python examples that ship
with the spark SDK, you'll see a file called stateful_network_wordcount that will show you how that all
works.
But the new way of doing all this stuff is called structured streaming.
And the idea there is that instead of using Dstreams and these distinct RDD's of data, we're just going
to model our stream as a data frame that just keeps on growing over time infinitely.
So this is kind of the new way of doing it.
Python support for structured streaming is still relatively recent but this is the direction that they're
pushing their Scala customers in and really people in general this is kind of the the new fangled way
of doing streaming.
The idea is that you just have a data stream feeding into this unbounded table, this unbounded data frame and
as new data arrives it just results in new rows being appended to that input table. And there are a few
advantages of this way of thinking,
so one is because you can just think of it as a data frame and process it like any other data frame,
your streaming code ends up looking a lot like the non streaming code for dealing with the same kind
of data.
So it makes development a little bit easier.
You can start with just a static data frame of data that's sitting on your harddrive somewhere, write
all the code for processing and analyzing and doing whatever you want to that data frame and then it's
a very slight modification to modify that to deal the stream of data instead.
So it makes development a little bit easier.
It's also useful because other systems within Spark are also moving toward data frames as an
API, so MLLib again is also moving toward data frames as its primary interface and especially in Spark
3,
that's definitely the direction they're going. In fact the RDD interfaces will probably go away sometime
soon entirely.
And the nice thing is that by using data frames as the API to structured streaming, we can interoperate
more easily with things like MLLib, so it would be simple for example to take a streaming data source
and feed that into a machine learning library algorithm using a data frame API.
With that let's look at an example and make it real and show you that this stuff actually works.