Let's start talking about what to do when things go wrong with our spark job.
It has a Web based console that we can look at in some circumstances.
So let's look at that first let's talk a little bit about troubleshooting spark jobs on a cluster and
you know honestly it's a little bit of a dark art.
I mean usually if it's not immediately obvious from the output of the spark driver script what's going
on.
A lot of times what you end up doing is just throwing more machines out it throwing more memory at it.
You know like we looked at with the executor memory option there.
But if you're running on your own cluster at least two or one that you have within your own network
SPARC does offer a console UI that runs by default on Port 40 40 and it does give you a little bit more
of a graphical in-depth look as to what's going on in a way to access the logs and see what executor
is doing what.
And that can be helpful in understanding what's happening now unfortunately an elastic map reduces pretty
much next to impossible to actually connect to Spark's UI console from outside of Amazon's network.
But if you have your own your own cluster running on your own network it might be a good option for
you.
So just so you see what it looks like in case you end up using a spa cluster that's run by your employer
or something where you do have access to the console.
Let's take a look at it just running on our local machine So we'll kick off a larger similarities build
script and take a peek at it see what it looks like.
So real quick let me show you the spark UI.
The console if you ever need it if you're running on a if you have local network access to your master
node on your cluster then you should be able to access this on Port 40 40.
So we kick off a script that takes at least a minute here our original movie similarity script here
on my desktop and we'll kick that off and as soon as that starts I can open a browser and navigate to
a local host colon 40 40 to open up port 40 40 my computer and you can see here we have this display
of any active jobs currently running and we can click through on that to drill in and see some cool
stuff.
We have the international visualization of the directed a civic graph that spark used.
We have a timeline here that we can use for troubleshooting where all the time is being spent in our
job for example.
So we could click on one of these and get more details on that stage and you can just drill down there
and try to figure out what's taking all the time and what you might need to optimize what I might need
to be partition better.
Now the useful thing is the environment tab here which tells you all the various passing dependencies
and software versions that are installed.
So if you're running on a cluster that you don't necessarily have direct control over that can be useful
information.
And I think our job already finished.
But I pretty much showed you everything we can kick it off again just to go through it again so executors
actually shows individual executors and you can drill into thread dumps and actually see what's going
on here in as much depth as you want to
the stage is tab also shows you details on each individual stage running.
So yeah if you need to get more insight into where your spark job is that where it might be stuck at
and things you might need to optimize this gives you all the information you might need.
So it's actually pretty slick.
There you have it.
And there you have the spark console as I mentioned.
It's hard to get to on EMR though that might change in the future.
And I hope it does.
But if you're running on another cluster that you have more direct access to or even within your own
network it's a good way to figure out what's going on and get a good sense of how long different steps
are taking.
You can also just watch the output of your driver's script to get a good sense of what's going on as
well.
But obviously the UI will give you a better sense of what's happening under the hood let's talk about
some more troubleshooting tips next.
Let's start talking about what to do when things go wrong with our spark job.
It has a web based console that we can look at in some circumstances.
So let's look at that first. Let's talk a little bit about troubleshooting spark jobs on a cluster, and
you know honestly, it's a little bit of a dark art.
I mean usually if it's not immediately obvious from the output of the spark driver script what's going
on,
a lot of times what you end up doing is just throwing more machines out it throwing more memory at it.
You know like we looked at with the executor memory option there.
But if you're running on your own cluster at least, or one that you have within your own network
Spark does offer a console UI that runs by default on Port 40 40, and it does give you a little bit more
of a graphical in-depth look as to what's going on, in a way to access the logs and see what executor
is doing what.
And that can be helpful in understanding what's happening now. Unfortunately an elastic map reduces pretty
much next to impossible to actually connect to Spark's UI console from outside of Amazon's network.
But if you have your own cluster running on your own network, it might be a good option for
you.
So just so you see what it looks like in case you end up using a spark cluster that's run by your employer
or something where you do have access to the console.
Let's take a look at it just running on our local machine. So we'll kick off a larger similarities build
script and take a peek at it see what it looks like.
So real quick let me show you the Spark UI.
The console if you ever need it if you're running on a if you have local network access to your master
node on your cluster then you should be able to access this on Port 40 40.
So we kick off a script that takes at least a minute here our original movie similarity script here
on my desktop and we'll kick that off and as soon as that starts I can open a browser and navigate to
a local host colon 40 40 to open up port 40 40 my computer and you can see here we have this display
of any active jobs currently running and we can click through on that to drill in and see some cool
stuff.
We have the international visualization of the directed a civic graph that spark used.
We have a timeline here that we can use for troubleshooting where all the time is being spent in our
job for example.
So we could click on one of these and get more details on that stage and you can just drill down there
and try to figure out what's taking all the time and what you might need to optimize what I might need
to be partition better.
Now the useful thing is the environment tab here which tells you all the various passing dependencies
and software versions that are installed.
So if you're running on a cluster that you don't necessarily have direct control over that can be useful
information.
And I think our job already finished.
But I pretty much showed you everything we can kick it off again just to go through it again so executors
actually shows individual executors and you can drill into thread dumps and actually see what's going
on here in as much depth as you want to
the stage is tab also shows you details on each individual stage running.
So yeah if you need to get more insight into where your spark job is that where it might be stuck at
and things you might need to optimize this gives you all the information you might need.
So it's actually pretty slick.
There you have it.
And there you have the spark console as I mentioned.
It's hard to get to on EMR though that might change in the future.
And I hope it does.
But if you're running on another cluster that you have more direct access to or even within your own
network it's a good way to figure out what's going on and get a good sense of how long different steps
are taking.
You can also just watch the output of your driver's script to get a good sense of what's going on as
well.
But obviously the UI will give you a better sense of what's happening under the hood let's talk about
some more troubleshooting tips next.