Ok real quick let's go through how to get set up on Amazon Web Services and create an account that you
can use to spin up your own plastic map reduce cluster for running spark jobs on the Cluster.
We'll also talk about how you can connect to that cluster because going forward you're not going to
be running your spark drive or scripts on your desktop anymore.
You're going to be running them from a master node on an easy to Linux instance in the cloud.
So you're going to have to be able to connect to that easy to instance from your desktop.
Let's go over how to do that on Windows now all right.
So to get started with Amazon Web Services first we're gonna walk you through how to create an account
on NWS if you haven't already.
Just a quick pointer of where to go there and when we're done we're gonna figure out how to actually
connect to the instances that we might be spinning up on Web services so when we actually create a cluster
for SPARC we need a way to actually log into the master node on that cluster and actually run our script
there.
So to do so we need to get our credentials for logging into any instances that our SPARC cluster spins
up and we'll also set up a terminal.
If you're on Windows called putty and go through how to actually use that to connect to your instances.
So we walk you through that right now okay.
Let's go through how to set up an Amazon Web Services account if you need one and get started with an
elastic map produce and also figure out how to connect to our instances on a classic map reduce.
So again you know if you don't want to risk spending money you're gonna need some.
You're gonna need a credit card number to sign up for an account here it's gonna cost some real money
and it can actually add up.
So if you do just want to watch.
That's OK but if you want to follow along feel free just make sure that you're careful to shut down
and terminate any clusters that you spin up in the course of this course or else you're gonna rack up
a pretty significant bill and you get a sense of the current pricing you can click on the pricing tab
up here and go to products and services and look at easy to the Elastic Compute Cloud because that's
the primary costs of our clusters that will be spending up is just renting time on these computers.
And if you scroll down you can see what individual types of instances cost.
Now by default a EMR cluster for SPARC is going to spin up M3 X large instances and these are for you
15 gigabyte apiece instances.
So these are very beefy and twenty six cents per hour it may not sound like much but it can add up.
Okay.
I mean that's actually a very reasonable rate for a computer that that powerful I'll grant them that.
But if you're running 10 of these things in a cluster all of a sudden that's two dollars and 60 cents
per hour and if you're running 10 of these for 10 hours then you're now up to twenty six dollars.
Right.
So you've got to be careful that you shut these things down when you're done because they can add up
quickly if you were to run that for a whole month and not even realize it and just get the bill at the
end.
I don't even want to think about how much money that would be.
So do exercise caution if you're going to do this yourself but if you are confident in your ability
to shut things down when you're done and you have you know some extra money to spend by all means sign
up here and follow along with me otherwise let me incur the expense like I said I ran up about 30 dollars
in the course of developing this course.
So there you have it.
He made an account just click on the sign into the console link here up in the corner and I'm already
in there but if I wasn't already logged in you would see a screen that would allow you to either enter
your username and password or create a new one.
And at that point you could say create new account and it would ask you for all of your personal information
and credit card information and it would actually call you as part of a two factor authentication process
to make sure that you are who you are and after you get through all of that stuff which I won't bore
you with making you watch you should be eventually at a screen that looks like this which is the AWOL
console.
And if you need to get to it it's always available through this little cube icon here.
OK.
Now we're going to be doing a lot of work with EMR the elastic map reduce product from Amazon Web Services
and it's not just mass produced it's actually a managed Hadoop framework so it spins up a Hadoop cluster
for you.
And that actually includes SPARC as well.
So EMR it's not just for map produce anymore you can actually use the yarn component of Hadoop as a
cluster manager that spark runs on top of.
And by just kicking off an EMR cluster an Amazon Web Services you can very quickly get a master node
and as many client you know slave nodes as you want for the job that you have at hand and maybe one
is all you need.
Given that you have four cores and a pretty powerful computer but it gives you everything you need it
deploys all the software you need automatically so all you have to do is log into your master node on
the Cluster copy your script there and make sure any data that it needs is accessible to it and run
it.
And that's it.
So it's very easy to use.
But first you need a way to actually connect to those instances.
Once you've spun them up and to do so you're gonna need log in authentication credentials.
So to do that you're going to need to get a private and public key pair that you can use for signing
in to your EMR cluster.
So click on the easy to service here.
Easy to is the elastic compute cloud which is the underlying service that EMR uses to actually spin
up the different computers in the cluster.
So click on easy to meanwhile click on key pairs.
Over here and from here you want to click Create Cupid keep hair and name it something you'll remember
I already created one called Sparky.
So you might want to call it the same thing.
And when you hit create it will download to your Downloads folder a spark keyboard PCM file which contains
your public and private key pair.
Make sure you actually download that file and keep it somewhere safe and back it up somewhere because
once you've downloaded it here you can never get it again.
OK.
You can always create a new one if you need to.
But for security reasons they make it impossible to actually re download your public and private key.
And that's in case somebody breaks into your Ada U.S. console account.
They don't want them to be able to gain the credentials to actually get into all of the computers on
your cluster and rack up a big bill for you.
So I've already done that and downloaded it into my smart course folder and I have a spark kit OPM file
there.
And if you need if you're on Windows you're also going to need some sort of terminal application so
you can log into your master node on the cloud and actually get your scripts there and run them and
I recommend a program called putty that you can search for if you need a terminal for window and you
don't have it already.
It will bring you to a Web site that looks like this not very fancy and putting itself isn't very fancy
either but it works and you can either install the full Windows Installer here or you can just install
the pieces you need.
The only parts you actually need are putting it out EMC which is the terminal application itself and
putty Gen Daddy XY which we're going to need to convert our APM file that contains our public private
key pair to a PPA file that putty can use.
So I've already done that and downloaded them into my SPARC course folder hit pause if you need to do
the same.
And once you have that you can open up putty agenda EMC and click on load which you need to do is change
this dropdown for the file filter to all files and select your spark keyed up PCM file and it will load
that in in order to save it as a p p k file that putty can actually use.
You now need to save it as a private key.
I'm going to leave the key if the key passphrase empty because it just makes life a lot more complicated
when you're actually trying to use this this key file.
And as long as you have know good physical security for your desktop I wouldn't worry about it too much
if it does make you more comfortable to have a passphrase.
Put one in but you know it's not as necessary as you might think.
So I'm gonna click on save private key is going to say I don't have a passphrase but yeah that's that's
fine by me and I will save it a spark heat up.
I've already done this before so I already have one.
So I'm just gonna overwrite the one that I have and at that point you have a spark keyed up K file that
will let you log into any cluster that you spin up using the spark key.
Keep hair later on.
Now to actually use that PPA file within putty to open up putty itself and when you actually spin up
your cluster you'll get back a hostname that you can use to actually log into the master note of your
spa cluster.
But the first thing you'll want to do is go to the SSA tab here open it up and click on off and here
you'll select your K file.
And once you have that you can just enter in the hostname of the master node of your cluster and you
can log in automatically without having to sign in with the username and password.
And that's actually more secure that way.
So there you have it you have an EMR elastic map reduce Amazon Web Services account ready to go and
you have a terminal ready and able to connect to that cluster as soon as you spin it up.
So we want to make sure we have all these pieces in place beforehand because again time is money on
that cluster once we spin it up and we want to have everything we need ready to go.
So we are now at that point.
All right.
Now you have everything you need to spin up a cluster and connect to it.
I'm not going to connect to it just yet though because as soon as I spin up that cluster the clock starts
ticking and my bill is going to start getting run up.
We'll wait until the last second to do that because like I mentioned before this really costs money
and you should be very very careful if you're going to be running these clusters yourself if you forgot
to shut them down when you're done if you forget to terminate them you're going to get a very big bill
at the end of the month that bill is going to be a lot bigger than the cost for this course.
So I cannot caution you enough to be careful when you're experimenting with EMR and running SPARC in
the cloud so don't leave those instances running for that reason you might want to consider just watching
and following along with the videos here for now.
But if you do choose to follow along with me and do these activities hands on please just remember to
terminate your clusters when you're done OK.
With that final warning.
Let's move on.