Let's have a quick look at our movie similarities script we modified to run on the one million ratings
data set for movie lines will cover how we're going to address partitioning and this new script as well.
So let's take a look at that code.
OK so let's modify our movie similarity script to actually work on the 1 million rating datasets and
make it so it can run in the cloud.
On Amazon's elastic map reduce or any spar cluster for that matter.
So if you haven't already go grab the movie similarities 1 m one million python script from the resources
for this lecture and save it wherever you want to.
It's actually not that important where you say this one because we're not actually gonna run it on your
desktop anyway you just need to look at it and know where it is so open it up just so we can take a
peek and I'll walk you through the stuff that we've actually changed here.
Now first of all we've made some changes so that it uses the 1 million ratings data set from group lines
instead of the 100000 ratings data set.
So if you want to grab that go over to group lines dot org and click on data sets and you'll find it
in the movie lines 1 m data set to 1 million ratings and this is a little bit more current from 2003.
But you know still pretty high to date.
You know they do have a current dataset that is updated as of this month.
But you're going to need a pretty large cluster D to handle the 40 million plus ratings in that dataset.
Let's stick with one million for now.
Just to keep costs under control if nothing else.
Go ahead and download that if you want to.
And when you get it you'll see that it's structured a little bit differently and we need to account
for that in our script.
So first thing we do the name the movie I.D. the movie name lookup table is now in a file called movie
start date.
And what I'm gonna do is make sure that that file exists in the same directory as my script as my driver
script when I'm running this on the master note of my cluster.
So the function that just loads up that dictionary of movie I did a movie name is because it's gonna
look locally in our current directory for movie star debt and we know that that's actually delimited
by these double colon thing now which is kind of a new format but otherwise it's doing the same thing
as before.
You don't think the things that have changed.
Notice that we're loading the actual ratings data from S three.
This is Amazon simple stories service and that is actually a distributed and redundant data store.
So if you are going to be dealing with really big data often it's data that's going to be living in
the cloud itself on some distributed file system.
And if you have a h DFS data store you could also have an HD DFS your URL here if you wanted to.
This basically tells spark go out to Amazon's as three service with this as three n euro look in the
sun dog dash spark bucket that I've created and under there it knows where to find the large ratings
dot that file that I got from the group lends one million ratings data set.
So technically speaking you should install this yourself in your owner's three bucket because you know
you're not supposed to you're supposed to go get it from their website and not from me.
That's according to their license agreement but hey secret's safe with me.
The are things changed here is the format of that dating of that data file for ratings has also changed
it's also delimited by these double colon characters.
That's the only change I've made there and one other thing worth pointing out is when I'm creating my
spa context notice that my spark conf object is empty I'm not putting anything in here at all for what
the Master is or what the name is because instead I'm going to pass that on the command line when I
actually run the script on the master and by doing so I can take advantage of some pre configure reconfigured
stuff on EMR elastic map reduce that will automatically tell spark to run on top of Hadoop yarn using
the cluster that I've created using EMR.
So if I were to actually keep my master equals local here it would only run on the master node and that's
certainly not what we want.
So by leaving that empty it will fall back to the command line arguments and the built in configuration
files for spark that Amazon sets up for me.
So that's a very important point.
If I did not change that I wouldn't really be running on a cluster at all and I wouldn't have very good
results.
So that's pretty much it.
I mean the main difference is here again just to recap or that I've moved my text file to be in the
cloud from S3 I have left my SPARC configuration empty and I've changed the format in the file names
of the data file to actually account for the differences between movie lenses one million rating data
set and the 100000 rating set.
So we're just about ready to start spending things up and start playing with it.
Everything else is pretty much the same one other note is that the ideas for movies have changed between
the 100000 and 1 million movie rating data set.
So Star Wars is no longer movie 1850 it's movie 260 and I left myself a little bit of a cheat sheet
up here as to how to actually run this on the Cluster when we get there but we'll talk about that more
next.
All right our code is now ready to run on a cluster on a plastic map reduce using SPARC on multiple
machines.
So let's go find out how to do that.
What do we have to do to run a script on a cluster.
Let's find out.
Let's have a quick look at our movie similarities script we modified to run on the one million ratings
data set for movie lens. We'll cover how we're going to address partitioning, and this new script as well.
So let's take a look at that code.
OK so let's modify our movie similarity script to actually work on the 1 million rating datasets and
make it so it can run in the cloud,
on Amazon's elastic map reduce, or any spark cluster for that matter.
So if you haven't already, go grab the movie similarities one million python script from the resources
for this lecture and save it wherever you want to.
It's actually not that important where you say this one, because we're not actually gonna run it on your
desktop anyway. You just need to look at it, and know where it is. So open it up, just so we can take a
peek and I'll walk you through the stuff that we've actually changed here.
Now first of all, we've made some changes so that it uses the 1 million ratings data set from group lens
instead of the 100000 ratings data set.
So if you want to grab that, go over to grouplens dot org and click on data sets and you'll find it
in the movie lens 1 m data set to 1 million rating,s and this is a little bit more current from 2003.
But you know still pretty out of date.
You know they do have a current dataset that is updated as of this month.
But you're going to need a pretty large cluster D to handle the 40 million plus ratings in that dataset.
Let's stick with one million for now.
Just to keep costs under control if nothing else.
Go ahead and download that if you want to.
And when you get it you'll see that it's structured a little bit differently, and we need to account
for that in our script.
So first thing we do. The movie I.D., the movie name lookup table is now in a file called movies
dot dat.
And what I'm gonna do is make sure that that file exists in the same directory as my script, as my driver
script when I'm running this on the master node of my cluster.
So the function that just loads up that dictionary of movie ID to movie name is because it's gonna
look locally in our current directory for movies.dat and we know that that's actually delimited
by this double colon thing now, which is kind of a new format but otherwise it's doing the same thing
as before.
You don't think the things that have changed.
Notice that we're loading the actual ratings data from S3.
This is Amazon Simple Storage Service, and that is actually a distributed and redundant data store.
So if you are going to be dealing with really big data, often it's data that's going to be living in
the cloud itself on some distributed file system.
And if you have a HDFS data store you could also have an HDFS URL here if you wanted to.
This basically tells spark to go out to Amazon's S3 service with this S3N url, look in the
sun dog dash spark bucket that I've created, and under there it knows where to find the large ratings
dot that file that I got from the group lens one million ratings data set.
So technically speaking, you should install this yourself in your own S3 bucket because you know
you're supposed to go get it from their website and not from me.
That's according to their license agreement, but hey secret's safe with me.
The other thing that changed here is the format of that dating, of that data file for ratings, has also changed,
it's also delimited by these double colon characters.
That's the only change I've made there. And one other thing worth pointing out is when I'm creating my
spark context,  notice that my spark conf object is empty, I'm not putting anything in here at all for what
the Master is, or what the name, is because instead, I'm going to pass that on the command line when I
actually run the script on the master. And by doing so, I can take advantage of some pre configured
stuff on EMR, Elastic Map Reduce, that will automatically tell spark to run on top of Hadoop YARN using
the cluster that I've created using EMR.
So if I were to actually keep my master equals local here it would only run on the master node.  And that's
certainly not what we want.
So by leaving that empty it will fall back to the command line arguments and the built in configuration
files for spark that Amazon sets up for me.
So that's a very important point.
If I did not change that, I wouldn't really be running on a cluster at all and I wouldn't have very good
results.
So that's pretty much it.
I mean the main difference is here again just to recap or that I've moved my text file to be in the
cloud from S3, I have left my Spark configuration empty and I've changed the format in the file names
of the data file to actually account for the differences between movie lenses one million rating data
set and the 100000 rating set.
So we're just about ready to start spinning things up and start playing with it.
Everything else is pretty much the same. One other note is that the ids for movies have changed between
the 100000 and 1 million movie rating data set.
So Star Wars is no longer movie id 50, it's movie id 260. And I left myself a little bit of a cheat sheet
up here as to how to actually run this on the cluster when we get there, but we'll talk about that more
next.
All right, our code is now ready to run on a cluster on Elastic map reduce using Spark on multiple
machines.
So let's go find out how to do that.
What do we have to do to run a script on a cluster?
Let's find out.