Next I want to talk about a few more troubleshooting tips with Spark.
There are some strange things that will happen at times, and some of them have happened to me in the
past.
It's not always obvious what to do about them either, so I'll share some of my experiences with that
and we'll talk about managing code dependencies within spark jobs as well.
So let's do that now. so let's talk about troubleshooting a little bit more, and I can tell you I did
need to do some troubleshooting to get that million readings job running successfully on my SPARK cluster.
So where are the logs?
I mean we saw some stuff scroll by from the driver script and in practice if you're running on EMR, that's
pretty much all you're gonna have to go on.
Now like I showed you, if you're in standalone mode and you have access directly on the network to your
master node, all the log information is just displayed in this beautiful graphical form and the web UI.
But if you're running on top of YARN, those logs end up getting distributed and you need to collect them
after the fact,
using this command. Yarn logs dash dash your application I.D., and use that to actually bring them
all back together so you can see them.
Your job is distributed.
And so the logs are distributed, and that makes them a little bit difficult to actually consolidate and
look at what's going on.
But you know a lot of times you kind of intuit what's happening. What happened with me when I was
trying to get this movie similarities with one million reading script running was that when I first
started running it, I kept getting errors in the driver's script that said that executors were failing
to issue heartbeats.
So I would kick off an executor to do some job, and that executor would just go away and never respond
again.
And it was you just got it hung right.
So when that happens it's probably a good sign that you're just asking too much of each executor.
So one thing is you can throw more machines at it.
And indeed, I found that by going up to 10 machines in my cluster, it ran a lot more reliably than with
you know four or five, and I might also mean that each executor may need more memory.
So even after doing that, they still hung unless I gave them one gigabyte per executor like we did earlier.
With the default value of 512 megabytes, it just wasn't enough.
Even with a hundred partitions.
And that brings me to the last point.
You can always increase the number of partitions in order to demand less work from each individual executor
job by using smaller partition sizes to split up your job into smaller bits.
So whenever you have executors that just get hung like that and they start issuing, they start losing
their heartbeat, spark's gonna start to try to destroy those executors and create new ones to try again.
But after about four tries, it's just going to give up in your entire job will fail.
So even though spark and Hadoop and yarn build themselves as being extremely fault-tolerant, at the end
of the day, if you're asking too much out of one of your executors and it just plain can't do it, your
job will still fail.
So don't rely on fault tolerance from Hadoop to ensure that your script will actually run successfully
because there is no such guarantee.
Now once you've configure things such that you are asking a reasonable amount of work from each executor,
then yeah fall tolerance does what it should be doing.
And if you have a genuine failure, if one of your nodes has some weird network error, then yeah it can recover
from that but nothing Hadoop does can recover from poorly structuring your code, having a wrong number
of partitions, having not enough memory or asking too much of each executor.
Those are problems you need to identify and fix before you put your job into production.
OK.
Another thing I want to talk about is managing dependencies.
So something to remember, even if something runs perfectly on your desktop, doesn't mean it will
run on your cluster, because you might not have the same Java environment, you might not have had the same
scale environment, you might not have the same Python environment; that could be an issue now.
Another point too is, like the same data won't be there, so if your scripts or if you're referring to
absolute file parts or file pass on your local desktop system, you're gonna want to make sure you fix
those before you run them on the Cluster.
One thing you can do is,  you know refer to a path that's on some distributed file system that each node has
access to, or you can use things like broadcast variables to actually share data outside of your RTD
and broadcast that to all of the nodes. But still your master node needs to get to that data somehow
originally before it can broadcast it to all the core nodes and you know try not to depend on obscure Python
packages.
Now if you do have a driver script that needs some weird Python package as a dependency, and it's not
preloaded on your Spark cluster, you can always set up a step in elastic map reduce to run Pip and
install whatever you need as it's in the process of spinning up each node.
There's also a dash dash pi dash files argument you can pass to spark submit to add individual libraries
and pass them off to the executor nodes.
But again that's only gonna work if you already have the packages you need on the master node, so you
kind of have this chicken and egg thing going on.
I mean Pip is probably the only realistic way to deal with this problem if you have to.
Otherwise, you still have to get what you need to the master node somehow, but honestly just try to avoid
using obscure packages if you can.
I mean time is money in your cluster, and the less time you spend fiddling with dependency issues the
better.
So if you don't need some weird package that doesn't come pre installed on your cluster, don't use it.
That's the best solution.
If you do need some weird cluster you can use, step in the EMR process to actually get that installed
as part of the bootstrap process for setting up your individual nodes.
And that is my brain dump on running spark in a cluster.
All right.
This concludes the part of the course about Sparks core.
You now know the things that you can do with Spark itself.
And we've done pretty much everything there is to do.
We've even run a million readings analyzed on a real cluster in the cloud using spark.
So congratulations, you're now pretty knowledgeable about spark if you got this far.
Next, we're going to talk about some of the technologies built on top of spark that are still part of
the greater spark package. And that will be our last section that includes sparks sequel, which is the
underpinning of the newer data frame API that spark is encouraging people to use going forward.
So don't skip this next section, as it is key to writing and understanding newer spark scripts.
So let's do that now!