Now that we're running on a cluster, we need to modify our script a little bit, our driver script.
We'll be looking at the movie similarity sample again and we're going to figure out how we can scale
that up to using a million movie ratings to do this.
We can't just run it as is and hope for the best.
If we were to do that it wouldn't succeed at all.
Instead we have to think about things like how is the state going to be partitioned.
And it's not hard but it is something you need to address in your script.
So let's cover partitioning next and how to use it in your SPARC scripts.
All right so let's talk about actually running our movie similarities scripts on a cluster and this
time we're gonna talk about throwing a million ratings at it instead of 100000 ratings.
Now if we were to throw this modify our movie similarities script to use the one million rating data
set from group lens dawg it's not gonna run your desktop obviously.
The main reason why is because when we do that self join to generate every possible combination of movie
pairs that blows up like you wouldn't believe and you're just gonna run out of memory and your job will
fail pretty quickly if you just run it on your desktop.
But even if you were to run it on and a cluster on a plastic map reduce with no matter how many computers
you throw at it it's still knock on Iran.
What will happen if you just run it as is.
Is that your executors will start failing and they'll just hang and you won't really know why and it's
it's not very easy to track down what's going on and you know there's a lot of things about sparked
that I love but one thing that's not so hot is that it does not automatically optimally spread out the
work of your job throughout a cluster.
You kind of have to think about that yourself and deal with it manually to some extent and that's where
a partitioning comes in.
So partition by is a method on an already D that you can use to say Hey I'm gonna run some large operation
and I know I have enough compute resources to actually split this up into many different executors many
different runs.
And that tells you basically how many pieces I want to break this job up into.
So if we actually call a partition buy on the RTD that we do a self join on First we can then split
it up into smaller chunks that are given executor can actually deal with and then our job will actually
complete successfully.
And once you do that any that partitioning will spark will attempt to preserve that partition and going
forward as much as it can.
So I want you to take a look at this list of different RTD methods join co group group with join left
outer join right our join group by key reduced by key combined by key and look up.
So these are very common.
We've definitely used group by key and reduced by key a lot and we've used join in this map produced
in this movie.
Similarities example already.
Anytime you're going to call one of these operations on a very large RTD they will benefit by using
partition buy on it beforehand.
So keep that in mind as part of your code review before running a large job on a cluster.
Look for places where you're calling any of these methods and ask yourself Do I need to call a partition
buy on it first.
Odds are you do.
OK so how do I choose the argument for partition by how many partitions is the right partition size.
So.
Well if you have too few partition then we'll take full advantage of your cluster it can't spread it
out effectively but if you have too many you know you end up shuffling data around and breaking things
up into two small chunks and there's some overhead associated with running an individual executive job.
So you don't want too many executives either but you want at least as many partitions as you have cause
in your cluster or as many will fit in your available memory so you know a hundred is usually a reasonable
place to start.
Let's say you have you know five or ten computers in your cluster that will split it up into a reasonable
amount of operations.
And I found that one hundred actually worked well on my own example here across a cluster of ten computers.
So let's go back and make some modifications to our movie similarity scripts to both make it work on
the one million reading datasets and also to make it work on a cluster by making sure we think about
partitions.
OK.
At this point we know about partitioning.
We now have the tools we need to go back to our movie similarity script and modify it so it will run
efficiently on a cluster with a much larger set of ratings.
So let's do that next.
Now that we're running on a cluster we need to modify our script a little bit our driver script.
We'll be looking at the movie similarity sample again and we're going to figure out how we can scale
that up to using a million movie ratings. To do this,
we can't just run it as is and hope for the best.
If we were to do that, it wouldn't succeed at all.
Instead, we have to think about things like, how is the state going to be partitioned?
And it's not hard, but it is something you need to address in your script.
So let's cover partitioning next and how to use it in your Spark scripts.
All right, so let's talk about actually running our movie similarities scripts on a cluster. And this
time, we're gonna talk about throwing a million ratings at it instead of 100000 ratings.
Now if we were to throw, you know just modify our movie similarities script to use the one million rating data
set from grouplens.org, it's not gonna run your desktop obviously.
The main reason why is, because, when we do that self join to generate every possible combination of movie
pairs, that blows up like you wouldn't believe, and you're just gonna run out of memory and your job will
fail pretty quickly if you just run it on your desktop.
But even if you were to run it on in a cluster on a plastic map reduce with, no matter how many computers,
you throw at it, it's still not gonna run.
What will happen if you just run it as is,
is that your executors will start failing, and they'll just hang, and you won't really know why, and it's
not very easy to track down what's going on. And you know, there's a lot of things about spark
that I love, but one thing that's not so hot is that it does not automatically optimally spread out the
work of your job throughout a cluster.
You kind of have to think about that yourself and deal with it manually to some extent, and that's where
a partitioning comes in.
So partition by is a method on an RDD that you can use to say 'Hey I'm gonna run some large operation
and I know I have enough compute resources to actually split this up into many different executors, many
different runs'.
And that tells you basically how many pieces I want to break this job up into.
So if we actually call a partition by on the RDD that we do a self join on, first, we can then split
it up into smaller chunks, that a given executor can actually deal with. And then our job will actually
complete successfully.
And once you do that, that partitioning, spark will attempt to preserve that partition and going
forward as much as it can.
So I want you to take a look at this list of different RDD methods, join, co group, group with join, left
outer join, right outer join, group by key, reduced by key, combined by key and look up.
So these are very common.
We've definitely used group by key and reduced by key a lot. And we've used join in this,
in this movie
similarities example already.
Anytime you're going to call one of these operations on a very large RDD, they will benefit by using
partition by on it beforehand.
So keep that in mind as part of your code review before running a large job on a cluster.
Look for places where you're calling any of these methods and ask yourself, 'Do I need to call a partition
by on it first?'.
Odds are, you do.
OK, so how do I choose the argument for partition by ,how many partitions is the right partition size?
So.
Well, if you have too few partitions then it won't take full advantage of your cluster; it can't spread it
out effectively. But if you have too many, you know, you end up shuffling data around and breaking things
up into too small chunks. And there's some overhead associated with running an individual executor job.
So you don't want too many executors either, but you want at least as many partitions as you have cores
in your cluster,  or as many will fit in your available memory. So you know, a hundred is usually a reasonable
place to start.
Let's say you have you know, five or ten computers in your cluster that will split it up into a reasonable
amount of operations.
And I found that one hundred actually worked well on my own example here across a cluster of ten computers.
So let's go back and make some modifications to our movie similarity scripts, to both make it work on
the one million reading datasets, and also to make it work on a cluster by making sure we think about
partitions.
OK.
At this point we know about partitioning.
We now have the tools we need to go back to our movie similarity script and modify it so it will run
efficiently on a cluster with a much larger set of ratings.
So let's do that next.