It's time to graduate off your desktop computer and start running some spark jobs in the cloud on an
actual spark cluster.
The easiest way I know of to actually get up and running if you don't already have a spark cluster is
by using Amazon's elastic map reduce service even though it says map reduce in the name you can actually
configure it to set up a spark cluster for you and run that on top of Hadoop and it sets everything
up for you automatically.
So let's walk through what elastic map produces how it interacts with Spark and how to decide if it's
something you really want to be messing with.
Okay let's talk about running spark on an actual cluster of computers in the cloud and getting off your
desktop.
So an easy way to get started if you don't really already have a cluster to run on is by using Amazon's
elastic map reduce service and it's an easy way to rent just the time you need on a cluster to actually
run your spark job and it makes things pretty easy.
So even though it says map reduce in the name it actually installs spark for you by default as well
and you don't have to just run mass produce jobs you can actually run spark and use the underlying Hadoop
environment to actually run as he or your cluster manager.
So yeah it has something called Hadoop yarn and if you took my earlier class on map reduce and Hadoop
you've heard about that already.
But basically yarn is dupes cluster manager and spark is able to run on top of it and that is all.
Also installed as part of elastic averages for you.
So let's back up a little bit.
I mean this is a service offered by Amazon.com.
Basically what you're doing is renting time in there.
There are you know massive data centers of computers and you're saying I want to like rent you know
six or seven different instances of computers I want to run my cluster across and instead of actually
buying those computers you're just paying by the hour now spark also has its own built in standalone
cluster manager and you can actually use that to run on easy to and has scripts to support that as well.
But I find that if you're gonna be using easy to anyway you may as well just use the Amazon Web Services
console application on the Web to launch a smart cluster that's already set up for you.
And then all you have to do is assess each into the master node in your cluster and copy your script
over and run it from there directly and I think that's a lot more straightforward than trying to figure
out how to use the easy to use scripts especially from Python it gets a little bit tricky.
Now I do want to warn you that if you did go through my earlier class on map reduce and Hadoop we also
used a classic map produced in that course and it was dirt cheap and the reasoning was dirt cheap is
because we were using dirt cheap instanced types which is basically the kind of computer that we're
using in our cluster but was spark by default.
We're using something that's a little bit more expensive actually a lot more expensive and those are
M3 dot ex large instances.
So even though we'll see that spark runs a lot faster.
Bear in mind we're using much more powerful computers than we did in the previous course and myself
personally I racked up about 30 dollars in Amazon Web Services charged developing this course so I had
to run the jobs are gonna go through to do movie recommendations on the cluster you know four or five
times and then ended up running about 30 dollars and that was me being very careful about only spinning
up these clusters when I needed them and terminating them as soon as I was done with them.
So they add up quickly.
So please if you are gonna follow along remember shut down your clusters when you're done or else you're
gonna rack up a very big bill very quickly and you're not going to be very happy about that.
Now if that makes you nervous you know if you don't think you have the discipline to actually remember
to come back and shut down that cluster and terminate it when you're done running it.
Maybe you shouldn't actually follow along with this and just watch me do it because there is a very
real risk here that you could run up a very large bill very quickly accidentally if you're not careful.
OK.
Now if you do have a corporate account with Amazon Web Services and you're doing this on somebody else's
dime maybe that's a different story.
Or if you already have a cluster for spark that you already have access to through your employer that's
running all the time by all means use it.
I'm just gonna walk through this as an alternative.
So you have a way of experimenting with Spark on a cluster from home.
If you want to play along.
But again please make sure after your jobs are done you need to manually terminate them in the in the
console and I'll show you how to do that later.
And the other important point to make sure that you keep your costs under control is to always run things
locally on your desktop on a subset of your data.
First remember we have operations on RTD like top and sample that you can use to create a smaller sample
of a data set and by doing that you can create a subset that you can use to work the initial kinks out
of your system at least and then when you're actually running on the Cluster hopefully the only bugs
you're dealing with are things that are specific to running on a cluster and that will save you a lot
of time and money.
So with that all said let's take a look at Amazon Web Services and how to set up an elastic map reduce
account and then we'll move on from there.
Well that's the elastic map produced in a nutshell.
If it seems like something you want to get down and dirty with and create a natively U.S. account I'll
walk you through some of the basics on how to get started with that next.
I'll also go over how to connect to it using a terminal for a Windows system.
It's time to graduate off your desktop computer and start running some spark jobs in the cloud on an
actual spark cluster.
The easiest way I know of to actually get it up and running if you don't already have a spark cluster is
by using Amazon's elastic map reduce service. Even though it says map reduce in the name, you can actually
configure it to set up a spark cluster for you and run that on top of Hadoop. And it sets everything
up for you automatically.
So let's walk through what elastic map produces, how it interacts with Spark, and how to decide if it's
something you really want to be messing with.
Okay let's talk about running spark on an actual cluster of computers in the cloud and getting off your
desktop.
So an easy way to get started if you don't really already have a cluster to run on is by using Amazon's
elastic map reduce service. And it's an easy way to rent just the time you need on a cluster to actually
run your spark job and it makes things pretty easy.
So even though it says map reduce in the name, it actually installs spark for you by default as well.
And you don't have to just run map reduce jobs, you can actually run spark and use the underlying Hadoop
environment to actually run as your cluster manager.
So yeah. It has something called Hadoop YARN, and if you took my earlier class on map reduce and Hadoop,
you've heard about that already.
But basically, YARN is Hadoop's cluster manager and spark is able to run on top of it, and that is all
also installed as part of elastic mapreduce for you.
So let's back up a little bit.
I mean this is a service offered by Amazon.com.
Basically what you're doing is renting time in there.
They are, you know, massive data centers of computers, and you're saying I want to like, rent, you know
six or seven different instances of computers I want to run my cluster across, and instead of actually
buying those computers, you're just paying by the hour. Now spark also has its own built in standalone
cluster manager, and you can actually use that to run on EC2 and has scripts to support that as well.
But I find that if you're gonna be using EC2 anyway, you may as well just use the Amazon Web Services
console application on the web, to launch a smart cluster that's already set up for you.
And then all you have to do is SSH into the master node in your cluster and copy your script
over, and run it from there directly. And I think that's a lot more straightforward than trying to figure
out how to use the easy to use scripts. Especially from Python it gets a little bit tricky.
Now I do want to warn you that if you did go through my earlier class on map reduce and Hadoop, we also
used a classic map produced in that course, and it was dirt cheap. And the reasoning it was dirt cheap is
because we were using dirt cheap instance types.which is basically the kind of computer that we're
using in our cluster. But with spark, by default,
we're using something that's a little bit more expensive, actually a lot more expensive, and those are
M3 dot x large instances.
So even though we'll see that spark runs a lot faster,
bear in mind we're using much more powerful computers than we did in the previous course. And myself
personally, I racked up about 30 dollars in Amazon Web Services charges developing this course. So I had
to run the jobs we're gonna go through to do movie recommendations on the cluster, you know, four or five
times. And then ended up running about 30 dollars. And that was me being very careful about only spinning
up these clusters when I needed them and terminating them as soon as I was done with them.
So they add up quickly.
So please, if you are gonna follow along, remember shut down your clusters when you're done, or else you're
gonna rack up a very big bill very quickly. And you're not going to be very happy about that.
Now if that makes you nervous, you know, if you don't think you have the discipline to actually remember
to come back and shut down that cluster and terminate it when you're done running it,
maybe you shouldn't actually follow along with this, and just watch me do it. Because there is a very
real risk here that you could run up a very large bill very quickly accidentally if you're not careful.
OK.
Now if you do have a corporate account with Amazon Web Services and you're doing this on somebody else's
dime, maybe that's a different story.
Or if you already have a cluster for spark that you already have access to through your employer that's
running all the time, by all means use it.
I'm just gonna walk through this as an alternative,
so you have a way of experimenting with Spark on a cluster from home
if you want to play along.
But again please make sure after your jobs are done, you need to manually terminate them in the
console and I'll show you how to do that later.
And the other important point to make sure that you keep your costs under control is, to always run things
locally on your desktop on a subset of your data.
First remember we have operations on RDDs like top and sample that you can use to create a smaller sample
of a data set, and by doing that, you can create a subset that you can use to work the initial kinks out
of your system at least. And then when you're actually running on the cluster, hopefully the only bugs
you're dealing with are things that are specific to running on a cluster. And that will save you a lot
of time and money.
So with that all said, let's take a look at Amazon Web Services, and how to set up an elastic map reduce
account. And then we'll move on from there.
Well that's elastic map reduce in a nutshell.
If it seems like something you want to get down and dirty with and to create an AWS account, I'll
walk you through some of the basics on how to get started with that next.
I'll also go over how to connect to it using a terminal for a Windows system.