Ok.
It's time to run our similarity script on a spark cluster in the cloud on a plastic map reduce pretty
big deal.
This is kind of the culmination of the whole course here.
So let's kick it off and see what happens.
So before we actually run our script on a spark cluster using Amazon's elastic map produced service
let's talk about some of the basic strategies that we're gonna use here.
So like we talked about before we're gonna use the default empty spark cough in the driver script in
that way.
Instead we'll use the default said elastic mass produced sets up for us and that will automatically
tell spark that it should be running on top of EMR as Hadoop ya in a cluster manager.
And that way it will automatically know what the layout of the cluster is.
You know who is the master.
How many client machines do I have.
Who are they.
How many executives do they have and what not.
Now when I'm actually running this I'm gonna need it pass one extra argument to spark submit.
So in the past we've always just called Sparks submit followed by the script name and whatever parameters
were passing into it.
But there's a bunch of other options you can pass into.
And specifically we're gonna pass in dash dash executor dash memory 1 G.
And that's because I know from past experience that if I try to run this with a default memory of 512
megabytes per executor that's not enough for that self join operation to actually succeed.
So by passing an executor memory 1 g I'm saying I want one gigabyte of memory per executor and that
should give me plenty to work with you know throughout that partition that's been broken up into one
hundred partitions for that self join anything lower just won't work.
Really the only way to figure this out is through trial and error unfortunately.
So you know I tried the default setting of five controlled megabytes my executors kept failing increase
it to one gigabyte and everything was happy.
So no real science to it.
You know you just have to experiment what works and try to do that experimentation as quickly as possible
because time is money on these clusters.
So.
So yeah there are other options you can pass in as well for example dash dash master yarn will tell
sparks submit explicitly to run on a yarn cluster but EMR actually sets that up for us by default.
However if you're running on your own cluster you might need to pass that in by hand.
Now ahead of time I've copied everything to Ada Lewis's S3 service just so I can access all of my scripts
and data files that I need quickly and I can use that to quickly copy over my script from S3 and also
refer to my large big data if you will using S3 and your URLs so that I can just load my data directly
from Amazon's S3 service.
One good thing about using Amazon Web Services EMR cluster is that it has very fast and very good connectivity
to S3.
So as three becomes a good choice for a distributed file system to use together with EMR.
You can also spin up an HD DFS file system as well if you want to.
All right so that's our next thing we'll do will be to spin up an EMR cluster for SPARC using the AWOL
console.
The clock starts ticking on our bill at this point as soon as those clusters become available we'll
get the external DNS name for the master node and log into it using putty and we will then copy our
driver program run it let it run and watch the output and as soon as we're done we're gonna terminate
that cluster so that so that we stop getting billed for that time.
Very important.
That's in all upper case and bold letters for a reason.
So if you do in fact follow along with me don't remember.
Don't forget turning the cluster over done.
So let's go and start the process.
All right it's time to actually run this script on a real spark cluster in the cloud.
And here we go.
So again remember that we're gonna be racking up some real charges here it's gonna cost real money to
run this on Amazon Web Services so feel free to follow along as long as you're careful to remember to
terminate your cluster when you're done.
You know it should only cost you a few dollars to run this once but if you have any doubts about your
ability to remember to terminate this cluster tone to it.
Just watch me do it OK.
It's gonna be cheaper and a lot safer that way.
But follow along at your own risk okay.
You have been warned.
All right.
Now to make life easier.
I've actually gone ahead and copy the one million email one M one million reading data sets to a sun
dog desk spark bucket on Amazon as three service so that my smart cluster can access it and I've also
copy the script itself to my son dog desk spark s three bucket as well so that way I can quickly obtain
it obtain a copy of it from my master note on my cluster so once I spin up that cluster first things
I'm gonna do because the know time is money the clock starts ticking right away.
I'm gonna call this little script to actually copy the movie similarities one MDR JPY script from S3
to that master node and then I'm going to copy over the movies dot that file that is kind of used to
load up and create that movie I did a movie name lookup table that is gonna use in the final output.
And finally I left myself a little cheat sheet here of what to actually run to execute this job.
OK so let's do it go to your go to the AWOL start Amazon.com console and we're gonna go to the console
to sign in and I'm gonna click on EMR
and I'm going to create a new cluster I'm gonna call it 1 million similarity or 1 million ratings more
specifically.
Right.
1 million ratings.
I don't really need logging because there's no easy way.
Easy way for me to look at it anyway.
I'm just gonna go ahead launch the cluster as opposed to using steps and we are going to use the latest
EMR release and we want primarily SPARC so to save a little bit of time I'm not gonna bother installing
Hive in my house and pagan stuff that I don't need.
I just want to spark one point five running on top of dupes ya and cluster manager and I will stick
with the default M 3 x large instances 3 of them.
Mm hmm.
Let's go with five
more is better.
All right.
For the key pair remember in the previous lectures we actually created a key pair and we need to select
that now.
So for me I'm using these SPARC Kiki pair.
This will correspond to the PPA file that you're gonna use to connect to your master node using putty
or whatever terminal you have.
And I will leave everything else as the default okay.
Here we go create cluster at this point.
The bill starts adding up.
So again don't hit this button unless you're comfortable spending a few dollars here and you're comfortable
with your ability to.
This cluster as soon as you're done using it.
OK if you're not comfortable with that.
Just watch me.
Here I go.
All right.
Now it's gonna take about five minutes for these to actually get provision.
So what's happening under the hood here is Amazon's Web Services framework is going out.
It's finding five available and three dot X large instances computers out there in its data centers
that I can have and it's gonna reserve those for me.
It's gonna install the operating system on them is gonna install spark and it's gonna install Hadoop
and that will take a few minutes.
So until this actually says you know stop saying provisioning and actually says that these systems are
actually ready to go and started we can't actually do anything quite yet.
So through the magic of video editing we're gonna cut here and I'm gonna come back in about five minutes
when these systems should be all spun up for me so I'll be right back.
Okay.
Through the magic of video editing we're back about five minutes later and sure enough my instances
have spun up so I now have a running master node of 1 and 3 x large instance and four core nodes of
an M three X large running as well.
So let's go ahead and without further ado connect to that and kick off our script because the bill is
going here and time is money so up here we have the public DNS name of our Master node.
And if you click on the SSA tab here we'll actually give you instructions on exactly what you need to
do to connect to it.
And we have connect.
We have instructions for both windows which I've been describing and also for Mac and Linux.
So if you are doing this from Linux or Mac OS this will tell you a little bit more detail what you need
to do.
Again you just need that spark keyed up VM file that we got from the key pair from easy to earlier and
you can type in something like this to actually connect into it.
But we are using putty.
So I'm going to copy this bit here which is what I need to type into the hostname field and go ahead
and open putty I want to piece that into the hostname and I'm gonna go to my SSD each section go to
off and select my PPA file that I created earlier and that should get me right in yeah yeah no we're
fine and there we are in that cute ask here.
All right.
Now it's time to get busy.
Let's kick this thing off.
So if you recall I left myself a little cheat sheet here in my script comments of what I need to do
so let's go ahead and do all of this.
First thing I will do is copy the script itself down so I typed in eight of us as three CPS three colon
slash our son dog spark slash movie similarities.
One m p y dot slash.
And what that's gonna do is go to s three and copy my python script my driver script here to this local
directory here in my home directory.
I also need the look up file for movie ideas to movie names so let's do that next day.
Alias s three C.P. has three columns last last Sunday August spark slash M.L. dash one m slash movie
start date also to the current directory and there we have that finally I'm going to kick off the job
itself.
Here we go.
Spark dash submit dash dash executor dash memory 1 g to give one gigabyte of memory per executor and
the name of the script.
Movie similarities.
1 M P Y.
And finally the movie ideas for Star Wars which I am interested in getting similarities for and off
we go.
All right I'm gonna let this go a little bit just to make sure everything's happy
you can see us doing all sorts of stuff and we're getting lots of info messages that we had filtered
out on our desktop configuration.
But while you're running on the cluster you want a little bit more insight as to what's going on in
case something goes wrong.
All right you can see here that it's already kicking off that sort by key operation here with 16 output
partitions doing all sorts of good stuff here.
All right I'm gonna come back later and we'll revisit this because this will take a little bit of time
to finish and we'll take a look at the results when it's done.
Well there we have it.
We've kicked off our job and it's running on a cluster at this point.
Pretty awesome.
I'd say we're actually you know doing big data now and we're running it on a spark cluster in the cloud.
So we'll let that run and take a look at the results in our next lecture.