OK.
Time has passed.
So let's review what happened and take a look at our results from our 1 million ratings movie similarities
run. All right, about 15 minutes later we have some actual results here to look at.
So let's take a look at what we ended up with.
After analyzing 1 million ratings and using that same script, our results were for the top similar movie
to Star Wars Episode 4 was Star Wars Episode 5.
Not too surprising, but the next sentence is a little bit surprising; some little movie called San Duro
that had a very high similarity score.
But let's look at what's going on there.
It's actual strength, the number of people that actually rated that together with Star Wars, is only 60.
So you know, I think it's safe to say that's kind of a spurious result. And now that we're using a million
ratings, we probably need to increase that minimum threshold on the number of creators in order to actually
display our results.
So by doing so, we could probably pretty easily filter out movies like that and instead get Raiders Of
The Lost Ark as our second result, which I think is interesting because it's actually scoring better
than Return Of The Jedi.
So you know I'm no film critic but maybe you too also enjoyed Raiders Of The Lost Ark more than Return
Of The Jedi.
I know I did.
So that's not that crazy.
We then get Run Silent Run Deep from 1958.
Again kind of a spurious result, with only one hundred and forty five co raters, and that doesn't sound
like, that sounds like a lot of people, but in the context of a million ratings not so much. So moral of the
story is, a lot of times you need to go back and kind of adjust your algorithms and clean your data a
little bit differently when you're running at a larger scale to get the results you want.
So data mining and using big data is not magic.
You do not automatically get better results just because you have more data.
In fact often the opposite is true.
So let that be a lesson to you.
But hey, we actually successfully ran this thing.
So that's a cool thing.
Let's shut down this cluster before we forget.
OK.
So now that I have a result, the most important thing is to remember to terminate that cluster.
So I don't keep getting billed for it.
That would be bad.
All right.
So let's go to the console dot AWS dot Amazon.com and I'm gonna click on EMR and find my cluster.
There it is, with the green circle next to it, meaning that that is currently running racking up a bill
for me.
But let's shut it down.
So let's click on that cluster and then click on terminate. Am I sure?
Yes. I'm going to lose everything I'm totally OK with that.
Just stop billing me for it.
All right.
You want to make sure that actually terminates, and that the status actually goes from running to terminated
and assuming you do, you will stop getting billed and that's all there is to it.
All right.
We have successfully run a one million ratings analysis on a cluster on a classic map produced using
on spark on top of Hadoop and we've shut down the cluster now that we're done with it.
Pretty cool.
And there you have it.
Movie similarities from one million ratings running on a cluster in a cloud on elastic map reduce
using spark.
Pretty awesome! Remember to terminate your cluster when you're done.
I'm going to keep saying that over and over and over again, because you really don't want that bill if
you're running this yourself. Terminate any clusters in the Amazon Web Services console using the EMR
tab.
OK. If you leave those running you're going to get a very big bill and you're not going to be happy.
But hey we got results.
That's awesome!
You are now officially processing big data in the cloud and that's what this course is all about.
So congratulations! Let's talk about troubleshooting jobs next and what you need to do when things go
wrong.